特效字幕  DR·Lee
■
米高梅电影公司
联美电影公司
洛奇 2
阿波罗在说  "来啊"！
Apollo is saying "Come on! "
阿波罗一直得分
Apollo is going right.
又一记左拳
Now he's gone for the left.
他一记左拳打中他
He's going for another right... another right.
单膝跪下
Down on one knee.
用拳套擦掉鼻子上的血
Lou Filippo in there wiping off the glove.
漂亮  左右组合拳
Aii right, a left and a right combination.
是什么支撑着他？让他越战越勇
What is keeping him up, Bill? I don't know.
他连举手防守的力气都没有了
He can't even get his gioves up to protect himself.
躺下！躺下！别起来！
Down! Down! Stay down!
阿波罗高举着双拳  在场上跳跃
Apollo's dancing around with his arms in the air.
五  六  七  八
Five...Six...seven...eight...
九
nine....
来吧
Come on.
阿波罗简直不敢相信！
Apollo can't believe it!
拳王右肋骨中一记左拳
He got a left to the ribs, his right ribs
你还好吧  拳王？
You okay, champ?
我还好
I'm okay.
他打断我的肋骨！
He broke my ribs!
我看不见  帮我把眼打开
I can't see nothing. You gotta open my eye.
替我割开  米克  我不要
Cut me, Mick. But I don't want to.
替我割开
Try anything. Cut it.
你内出血  我要终止这场比赛
You're bleeding inside, champ. I'm gonna stop the fight.
你不可以  没什么！
You ain't stopping nothing, man!
你阻止这场比赛  我就杀了你！
You stop this fight, I'll kill you!
我会杀了你！
I'll kill you!
你得在你倒地以前先把他击倒
You gotta get him down within the body.
第15回合也是最后一个回合
There is the bell for the 15th and final round.
你最好开始攻击
You better start fighting.
你都没有出击过
You're doing nothing.
他们好像是经历过一场大战
They look like they've been in a war, these two.
阿波罗拳王向他重击
Apollo, the champion, really tagged him.
阿波罗显然在护着他的右边肋骨
And Apollo clearly protecting his right side, his ribs.
看这一下！
look at that!
重击身体！
Belly punches!
重重的左右拳猛打！
Hard left and right!
看他的嘴巴出血了他吐掉血
look at the blood coming out.He's spltting out blood now.
一记左拳  他全身被打
A left
洛奇挥出重重的右拳
and he's already using his right hand.
加油！洛奇！
Go for it! Go for it, Rocky!
听这叫声  一记左拳中肋骨  又一记
listen to this crowd. A left to the ribs. Another to the ribs.
又一记左拳中打中肋骨！
That left hand again, that left hand!
正中脸颊！他把他逼到绳子上
Right to the chin! He's got him up against the ropes.
阿波罗这位拳王
Apollo, the champion
我再也不跟你比赛！
Ain't gonna be no rematch!
我也不要！
Don't want one!
洛奇  你居然打了15个回合！
You went the distance. You went the 15 rounds!
你有什么感想呢？
How do you feel?
艾黛丽安
Adrian
进入第15回合时你在想什么？
What did you think when it was the 15th round and you came out?
洛奇！
Rocky!
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen
请大家注意
Attention please.
洛奇！
Rocky!
我们很荣幸地能够亲眼看到
we have had the privilege of witnessing the greatest
拳击史上最佳勇气与耐力地表现！
exhibition of guts and stamina in the history of the ring!
艾黛丽安
Adrian
洛奇！
Rocky!
女士们  先生们  现在裁判不一致！
ladies and gentlemen, we have a split decision!
- 艾黛丽安！- 洛奇！
- Adrian!  - Rocky!
阿波罗·克利特以八票胜出！
Eight for Apollo Creed!
艾黛丽安
Adrian
你的拳迷要求重赛
Those fans out there deserve a rematch.
你还要不要再比赛？
Are you ready for it?!
不会有重赛！
Ain't gonna be a rematch!
今晚我这张脸受够了  艾黛丽安！
I had enough things in my face tonight!
洛奇！他是我朋友
Rocky! That's my friend,
洛奇
Rocky.
我的西装要破了！
You're breaking this jacket!
保利！
Paulie!
- 艾黛丽安！- 洛奇！
- Adrian!  - Rocky!
你的帽子在哪？
Where's your hat?
我爱你！我爱你！
I love you! I love you!
我爱你！
I love you!
我爱你！我爱你！
I love you! I love you!
我爱你！
I love you!
艾文·温克勒
罗伯特·恰托夫
制作
洛 奇       2
西尔维斯特·史泰龙
塔莉娅·夏尔
波特·杨
卡尔·韦瑟斯
布吉斯·梅迪斯
托尼·伯顿
乔·斯皮内尔
伦纳德·盖恩斯
约翰·普莱舍
比尔·鲍德温
原创音乐
比尔·康堤
剪辑
斯坦福·C·艾伦
美术设计
理查德·伯格
摄影指导
比尔·巴特勒
美国电影摄影师协会
制片人
艾文·温克勒
罗伯特·恰托夫
编剧及导演
西尔维斯特·史泰龙
洛奇·巴尔博亚
Rocky Balboa
让路！
Get 'em outta here!
让他喘口气！让一下  都让开
Let him breathe...will you?! Get 'em out of here! Give him air.
坐下  洛奇
Sit down, Rocky. Sit down, kid.
洛奇  你认为你赢了拳赛？
Rocky, did you think you had it won?
我说不上来
I don't know.
你说点什么吧  洛奇？
How about a statement, Rocky?
我拙于表达自己
I'm at a loss for words.
退后！
Get back there!
洛奇  你想赢了吗？
Rocky, did you think you had it won?
不清楚
I don't know.
医生在哪里？
Where's the doctor?
我的鼻子是否跟米奇的一样  ？
How's my nose look? As bad as Mickey's?
没有那么严重  好了  都别烦他！
It ain't that horrible. Give him a break!
洛奇
Rocky,
这是不是你被打得最惨的一次？
is that the worst beating you ever took?
你再不走  把你打得更惨！
You gonna get worse if you don't get outta here!
洛奇  最后一个回合时你在想什么？
Rocky, what did you think going into the last round?
不知道  我应该去读书
I don't know, that I should've stayed in school or something.
你会有脑损伤吗？
Do you think you have brain damage?
我没有发现
I don't see any.
他在哪？他在哪？
Where is he? Where is he?
阿波罗  说几句话
Apollo, how about a statement?
走开！
Get away from me!
好个种马  你头壳硬命大
I want the Stallion. You got the Gold Star, Stallion.
你太好运！简直是奇迹出现
You're lucky, so lucky! What you did was a miracle.
你是世上最幸运的人！
You are the luckiest man on the earth!
我看起来像吗？
Do I look lucky?
还没有人能跟我对抗得这么久的！
Look, nobody goes the distance with me!
我们现在就一决胜负  站起来
Get up out of that chair, chump, and let's finish this fight right now.
求你不要了
Don't, please. Sit down.
他可当真？
Is he serious?
阿波罗  是比赛铃声救了你吗？
When you were going down, did the bell save you, Apollo?
铃声不算什么！
Bell nothing, man! I can beat that chump!
我随时可以把那个呆子打倒！
I'll fight him anyplace, anytime!
重赛如何？
Does that mean there'll be a rematch?
我说了  随时随地奉陪！
I said anyplace, anytime, man!
阿波罗  可是你说过不再比赛的
Apollo, you said no rematch.
呆子  你听着
Look, chump,
随时随地奉陪！
anyplace, anytime!
洛奇  重赛或许价值数百万！
Rocky, a rematch could be worth millions!
我现在正式退休
I'm officially retired now.
你不要对我来这一套！
Don't you run out on me!
我第一次给你打赌输赢的机会
I gave you a shot the first time.
我现在又再度给你第二次机会！
Now I'm ready to give you a second shot!
他精力充足  你没什么好证明的
He sure has a lot of energy. You know, you got nothing to prove.
我不在乎裁判的决定
I don't care what the hell them judges said.
赢的人是他！
This is the man that won the fight!
我让你知道你命大！
I'm gonna show you how lucky you are!
你得再跟我比赛  呆子  回来！
You're gonna fight me again, chump. Come back here!
艾黛丽安  你先回家吧
Adrian, you better go home
治疗一时半会儿还完不了
because I'm gonna be busy healing here for a while.
我要留下！
I wanna be here!
不  跟保利一起回家吧  回家睡一觉
No, maybe you better go home with Paulie and get some sleep.
- 我爱你   - 我也爱你
- I love you.  - I love you.
回头见
See you later.
米克  回头见
See you, Mick.
你能否医医我的鼻子？
Can you fix my nose?
我对我的鼻子感到很失望
I'm a little depressed about my nose.
我们会替你医的
We'll fix that, all right.
我倒是担心你的眼睛
It's the eye that concerns me.
我的眼睛没问题
The eye is great, you know.
我从来没有感觉这么好过
I ain't never really feIt this good.
你们该看今晚的比赛
You guys should've seen us tonight.
我们打得精彩
We were good.
我一直希望的  你们该看
I always wanted to be. You should've seen it.
你在第十回就把他给制服  到了第15回合他便告不知了
You had him in the 10th and in the 15th, he was gone.
是吗？
You think so?
真的  我当时在场
Trust me, I was there.
你的脸怎么回事？洛奇
How's your face, Rocky?
我也不知道  看起来怎么样？
I don't know. How's it look?
我可不希望变成这样子
I wouldn't want it.
洛奇  帮个小忙.
Rocky, I got a little favor I'd like to ask you.
你知道  盖左特别欣赏你
You know your friend Gazzo? He admires you a lot.
去向他说让我去接替你过去工作
Tell him to give me your old job with him.
你是指收帐？
You mean collecting?
是呀  我对帐目最拿手的
Yeah, I'm good with numbers.
好的  等我这治疗工作一结束
Okay, as soon as I get finished, you know, healing here
就告诉他让你去作我的老工作
I'll tell him to give you my old job with him,
- 好吗？- 那就太谢谢了
- okay?  - I'd appreciate that.
你在这里作什么？
What're you doing here?
访客时间已过  你得走了
Visiting hours are over. I have to ask you to leave.
回头见  保利
Okay, I'll see you later, Paulie.
大家都以你为荣
Okay. Everybody's proud of you, Rocky.
是吗？是的！
Yeah? yeah!
我今晚觉得很好
l feel good tonight.
是呀  你看起来是很好  走吧
Yeah, ya look good. Let's go.
今晚有什么感受？
How are we feeling tonight?
很好
Very handsome.
味道不错
That tastes good.
我的小孩子直吵着要你亲笔签名
My kid would die for your autograph.
好呀
Sure.
能不能写上？
Would you sign it, please?
送给我的好朋友  查理·弗林
To my good friend, Charlie Flynn.
我的手好痛  不要紧
My hands are so sore.
这是我第一次为拳迷签名  谢谢
It's my first autograph. Thank you.
送给我的好朋友  籊里芬
To my good friend, Charlie Flynn,
他是谁我都不知道
whom I don't even know.
你是阿波罗吗？
You, Apollo?
谁呀？
Who is it?
是我  洛奇
It's just me, Rocky.
你是否能够回答我一个问题？
Listen, could you answer me one question?
可以呀
Yeah, sure.
你是否尽了全力在比赛？
Did you gimme your best?
是的
Yeah.
谢谢你
Thank you.
年近了  你还好吧？
This coming year, Rocky You all right?
我真高兴能出院
It feels great being outside.
你今年为我们挣足了30万美元
This coming year you gonna make $300,000 with us.
洛奇！洛奇！
Rocky! Rocky!
可以在我头上签名吗？
Could you sign my head?
好呀！
Yeah, sure!
希望你的头部安然无恙
I hope it don't go to your brain.
我敢保证那一定很重
I bet that's heavy.
是有一点
A little bit.
石膏一旦拆掉  你想要多敏捷就有多敏捷
Think how fast you'll be when you get it off.
借用你的脑袋一分钟
Let me use your head for a minute, kid.
洛奇  只要签个名
Just sign, Rocky, just seal the deal.
我们来谈看看
I want to talk to you about this here.
这是个如意算盘
It's a standard deal.
只谈刮脸用品的事？
Just for talking about shaving stuff.
长柄大锤  电池  任何东西
Sledgehammers, whatever, batteries.
各种电视广告
All kinds of commercials.
像球类与棒球类？
Like balIs and baseballs?
你就挣30万元  动作要快
You're gonna make $300,000. You gotta strike now while the iron's hot.
人们是很健忘的
People kinda forget, you know.
把握现在  这里签个字吧
The time is now. Here, sign it here.
只要花二秒钟就可以签好
It takes you two seconds to sign.
这是个如意算盘
It's a standard deal.
我会签的
I'll sign it,
不过我现在要去别的地方
but I gotta go now.
走哪？还有什么比这更重要的？
Where you going? What could be more important?
我会再回来  我有要事
I just gotta do some things, you know. I'll be back.
我会跟你谈的  给我电话号码
I'll talk to you or something. Where will we call you?
我会打电话给你  你的电话多少？
I'll call you. You got a number?
不  我打给你好了
No, I'll just call you.
好  你打
All right. You call. Here.
这家伙脑袋有问题
The guy's got brain damage.
能够出院又不要吃药真好
It's great being out of the hospital, not having to take all those pilIs and everything.
可是我的腿好痛呀
My legs were getting so sore and all that.
我只要卧在那里  觉得萎缩
From just laying there, I was kinda shrinking and all that.
能出院真好
It's great to be outside, you know.
我们来动物园作什么呢？
What are we doing here at the zoo?
我很喜欢这个动物园
You know, I kinda like this zoo a lot.
这是一个很特出的地方
It's a special place,
尤其是下雪的时候
especially when it snows.
有一种清新的感觉
It kinda smelIs clean and everything like that, you know.
你不喜欢动物园吗？
Don't you like the zoo?
我喜欢动物园
I like the zoo.
我也喜欢
Yeah, me too.
我在想例如
You know, I was wondering like
你未来的四五十年有什么打算？
what do you think you're doing for like the next 40 or 50 years?
你是什么意思？
What do you mean?
我在想假如.
I was wondering
你嫁给我应该不会很不爽吧？
if you wouldn't mind marrying me very much.
你在说什么？
What'd you say?
假如你嫁给我不会不爽吧？
If you wouldn't mind marrying me too much?
是  我愿意要嫁给你的
Yes. I'd like to marry you.
- 是吗？- 是的
- Yeah?  - Yes.
我一定当个好丈夫
I'll be a good guy, I promise.
我不作坏事
I ain't gonna do nothing wrong.
我不在水槽里掉落头发
I ain't gonna leave no hair in the sink
或其他类似的事情
or nothing like that, you know.
你可知道一切都会很理想？
Things are gonna be great, you know?
嘿  我们要结婚了！
We're getting married you know!
你要不要来参加婚礼？
You wanna come?
如果你周末能出来吗？
Can you get out for the weekend?
我要给你一张请贴  老虎先生！
I'll send you an invitation, Mr. Tiger!
简直是太棒了  不是吗？
That's fantastic, ain't it?
（意大利语）洛奇·巴尔博亚
Rocky Balboa.
你是否愿意娶艾黛丽安·佩里洛为你的妻子
( Speak in Italian )
是的  当然愿意
Absolutely. Yes.
艾黛丽安·佩里洛
( Speak in Italian )
你是否愿意嫁给洛奇·巴尔博亚为妻？
- 我愿意  - 谢谢
- I do.  - Thanks.
我现在宣布  你们结为夫妻
( Speak in Italian )
你可以吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride now.
得拿掉这个
I gotta take this off.
愿你们平安并求主赐福给你们
Go in peace and God bless you.
神父  谢谢
Thanks, Father,
你主持得很好  我以此为荣
you done real good. I'm proud of you.
恭喜  艾黛丽安和洛奇  谢谢！
Adrian and Rocky, congratulations!
洛奇  你要不要猫狗店来帮忙？
Rocky, you want to buy into the pet shop?
我要上电视作广告
I'm gonna do commercials.
电视广告？想干吗？引起轰动
Commercials? What for, a concussion?
了不起的神父
Isn't that Father something?
祝你们幸福  谢谢
Good luck to both of you
我得回拳馆去了
I gotta go back to the gym.
我发现一对有前途的运动员
I got a couple of good prospects.
- 他们真的那么好吗？- 是的 相当出色
- Are they really good?  - They're pretty good.
米奇  回头见  谢谢你来
I'll see you around. Thanks for coming.
对不起  我能借新郎一分钟吗？
Excuse me, can I borrow the bridegroom for a minute?
你真漂亮  艾黛丽安
You look beautiful, Adrian.
是啊  她变漂亮了
Yeah, she really turned out pretty.
上次的拳赛你挣多少钱？我是说  你拿到手多少？
How much money did you make from your last fight? How much did you clear?
大约三万七千元
About 37 grand.
我知道税很重  这些钱你打算怎么用？
l know taxes kill you. What you wanna do with your money now?
放债吗
You want to put 'em on the street.
托尼  我才刚刚结婚
Tony, I just got married in here.
我也为你高兴
I know, and I'm happy for you.
投资公寓大厦比较安全
How's about investing in condominiums? It's safe.
公寓大厦？
Condominiums?
对  公寓大厦
Yeah, condominiums.
我从来没用过
I never use them.
各位  你们在干嘛？
Hey, you, what are you doing?
洛奇  怎么啦？
Rocky, what's happening, man?
你们知道吗？我才刚刚结婚
You know, I just got a little married.
恭喜！
congratulations!
- 你们在干吗？- 我们在喝酒
-What are you guys doing?  - Getting some wine in?
接着唱  我喜欢听
Why don't you keep singing some more?
敬他与他的新娘
Sing somethin' for him.
他们是谁？
Who are they?
他们就像附近的点唱机一样
They're like a neighborhood jukebox.
我一直都不知道你这么轻
I never knew you were so light.
我如果早知道
No, if I did,
我就抱着你到各处去了
I would've carried you everywhere.
你累了吗？
Are you getting tired?
不  这样可以训练腕力
No, this is great for the arms.
我简直不敢相信我们已经结婚了
I can't believe we're married.
我口袋里有证书
I got proof in my pocket.
每件事都发生得这么快没错
Everything happened so fast.
不过我早就知道即将发生的事情
But I knew it was gonna happen from the start.
你又知道些什么？
What did you know?
第一次遇见你的时候
The first time I seen you,
我对我自己说
I says to myself, I says:
就算这女孩子非常害羞
Even though this girl is suffering from the disease of being shy
隐藏在毛衣与帽子之下
underneath them sweaters, and hat, and
你穿20件毛衣吗？
What'd you have on, about 20 sweaters?
不  三件
No, three.
你可知道穿三件毛衣在身体上  是最好的女孩子？
Three Sweaters is the best girl in Philly, you know?
对  我是这么说过  真的？
I said that. Really?
我们到了
we're gonna check this out.
布可斯你下来好吗？
Butkus, could you get down? Go on.
去找别的地方好吗？
Go find another seat, will you?
要我帮你脱吗？
You want me to help you with this?
我可不可以把这么拿下？
Can I take this off?
我喜欢你这个样子
That's the way I like you.
拥有你是我一生中最满意的事情
You know, you're the best thing that ever come into my crazy life.
知道吗？真的
You know that, huh? Really.
你是我所拥有最好的事物
You're the best thing that ever come into my life.
你看我们都会永远像现在一样吗？
You think it'll always be like this?
是
Yeah.
我希望你  怎样？
I hope you. What?
你永远都不会讨厌我
you never get tired of me.
不会
Oh, no.
好永远都不会背弃我
You ain't never getting rid of me.
我希望永远不变
I hope nothing changes.
我不会变  我向你保证
I ain't changing. I sure ain't
我对你是永远不变的
never changing nothing about you.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
好车  洛奇
It's a nice car, Rocky.
是部很好的车
It's a great car.
文件在这  多谢
Here's the papers for it. Thanks a lot. I appreciate it.
恭喜  谢谢  你也一样
Congratulations. Lots of luck. Same to you.
你看是不是很好？
Isn't that nice?
我们真的用不着车子
We really don't need a car.
我现在要作电视广告  艾黛丽安
I'm gonna be doing commercials.
我买得起车子  没问题
I can afford this, you know. No problem.
你会开车吗？
Do you know how to drive?
- 我会不会开车？- 你会开车吗？
- Do I know how to drive?  - Do you know how to drive?
我是最棒的司机！上车  我带你去兜一圈
I'm one of the greats! Come on, I'll drive you.
这看起来有点像灰姑娘与南瓜
This'll just be like Cinderella and the pumpkin, you know.
你会开车吗？我不会开车？
Do you know how to drive? Do I know how to drive?!
我会开飞机和推土机
I drive airplanes and bulldozers.
你给我一次机会让你过坐车乐趣
I'd drive you crazy if you'd give me a chance.
了解我意思吧？
You know what I mean?
看那边
Look at this here.
你穿这件大衣不是很漂亮吗？
Tell me that wouldn't look great on you?
这件外套很好呀
This one's okay.
这件黑衣服背面还有一只老虎
Look at this black thing here with a tiger on the back.
我喜欢黑色  你要买吗？
Black, I like black. It's kinda my favorite color. You wanna buy 'em?
我们赶快买  免得别人买去
We get 'em before someone else buys 'em. What do you say?
来吧  艾黛丽安
Come on, Adrian.
我认为这对她合适不过了
I think that would be perfect for her.
对  我也认为很不错
I think that's perfect, too.
那不是很贵吗？放心吧
Don't you think this is kind of expensive?
你想不想度过美好的时光？
Come on, do you like having a good time?
那么你就需要一只好表
Then you need a good watch.
我也要买一只送给保利  好吗？
I wanna get one for Paulie, too. Okay?
你自己也买一个吧？我？
What about one for yourself? For me?
我不太有时间观念
I can't tell time very good.
不过  我也买一个好了
But, all right, I'll take one, too.
格洛丽亚  有什么好看的？
Gloria, you got something nice for Butkus?
可以给布可斯戴？当然有
Sure thing, Rockyhead.
你喜欢吗？
You like that?
布可斯戴
Butkus, look at that.
你的颈子好漂亮  对不对？
Your neck looks great, huh?
有没有小一点的？有
Gloria, you got something a little smaller?
这个
Look at that.
看看这个
Oh yeah, look at that.
你看  这就是我说的高级货
You see? Now that's what I call class, huh?
很拉风的
Real sharp.
你还好吧？
You okay, Butkus?
那房子很不错
Nice house.
看看这些砖头  艾黛丽安
Look at these bricks, Adrian.
我先生对砖头最内行
My husband's an expert on bricks.
这些都是新的砖头吗？
Are these new bricks?
对  这四周都很坚固
This is a very solid neighborhood.
我喜欢这些  看起来很坚固
I like the bricks. They're very nicely done here. They look very solid.
信箱很漂亮  这些号码加起来是9
Nice box. I like this mailbox. These numbers almost add up to nine.
我喜欢这个数字  是好预兆
I like that. It's a good omen.
好房子
Nice house.
嘿  艾黛丽安
Adrian, baby,
那里放个软布袋最合适
that's a great spot for a bag.
那天我要教教你怎么使用那袋子
I could teach you how to work that bag someday, you know.
是否有铜水管的装置？
Does it have copper plumbing?
楼上和楼下都有
Upstairs and down.
整层房是用钢筋搭的支架
The whole house is supported with steel. The whole thing.
这些地板是用坚固的橡木的
All these floors are solid oak, solid.
包波亚太太
Mrs. Balboa,
你一定会喜欢这里的厨房
can I show you the kitchen? You're gonna really like it.
坚固是最好
Solid.
那里放个收音机最合适
Adrian, that's a great spot for a radio. Right over there, you know.
看看这些楼级  很好走
Look at these steps. Nice steps.
厨房是很不错
A nice kitchen.
每年的税要交多少？
What're the taxes every year?
一千五百元  一千五百元
Fifteen hundred. Fifteen hundred.
我喜欢  我一看就知道是好房子
I like it. I know a pretty good deal when I see one, too.
对不起  我想跟我先生讲个话
Excuse me, I want to talk to my husband for one second.
我跟你谈谈好吗？
Can I talk to you?
那当然  我没有约会
I'm available. I got no appointments.
洛奇  你轻易地就接受他的推荐
Rocky, you're making this man's job very easy.
银行第一次只能给我们
The bank says it will give us
一万六千元的货款
a $16,000 mortgage
9.5%的利息
at nine and a haIf percent.
我们来买下这层房子吧？
That don't matter. Let's get the house?
可是我们还没上楼去看看
But we didn't go upstairs.
只是看看装饰我就知道是不错
That's just details. I'm sure it's nice.
装饰？你有把握吗？
Details, huh? Are you sure?
没问题的
Absolutely, okay?
我们就买下这房子
We'll take the house,
最好是不要漏
and it better not leak, or else.
我跟我太太私下谈谈好吗？
Could you stand over there? I gotta talk secretly with my wife.
- 当然   - 谢了
- Sure.  - Ok.
我觉得开着灯谈很滑稽
You know, I kinda feel stupid, talking like this with the lights on.
但是这房子
But the house here,
这坚固的橡木地板  铜水管
the solid oak floors and all that stuff and the plumbing
如果这房子没有你来住  就变得没有意义了
wouldn't mean nothing without you being here
假如不是你  你是知道的
I don't know, without you being here, I'd probably
我也不会来看这房子的
I wouldn't be here either, you know.
你不必说了
You don't have to speak.No?
好了  我们去庆祝一番
Okay, let's go celebrate.
我要把你推下池里！
I'll beat you to the pool!
嘿  慢点！
Hey, you guys! Slow down.
马丽安  听听这个
Mary Anne, hon, listen to this.
你并没有把对方击败
You didn't beat nobody and anybody
这比赛事先就预定好胜负
who knows boxing knows the fight was fixed.
伦敦来的信说
This one came from London.
你自称是拳王  你是冒牌的
You call yourseIf 'The Champ.' You're a fake
你自己去死吧
The fight was a fake. Go kill yourself.
干嘛要浪费时间  来看这些可恶的信件呢？
Wouldn't you rather play with the children than read hate mail?
你受了多少钱  跟那无赖打满了15回合？
How much did you get to carry that bum for 15 rounds?
你让黑人太丢脸了
You're a disgrace to your people.
你可以不理它！
Why can't you ignore it?!
你当真的吗？
Are you serious?
快  我要打击了
Let me get you in focus.
你准备好了？好了
You ready, man? All right, I'm ready.
你瞎了吗？
Are you blind, Rocky?
你少来了  快投球
What're you getting wise with me? Throw the ball,
露两手吧  我等你  我等你
let me see your best, here. I'm waiting for you.
我准备好了
I'm waiting for you.
你碰都没碰上！
You can't even play stickball!
我准备好了  我刚刚作了热身  准备好没？
Come on, I'm ready now. I'm just warming up.Are you ready for this?
你少叫了  就这个方向
You better keep your mouth closed. It's coming in that direction.
好棒！
What a shot! Over the roof!
我就知道今天没有白过
Now I know this day weren't no waste.
有了吗？有了
Yeah? yes
艾黛丽安  你办到了！
Adrian, you did it!
你今早醒来微笑着
You woke up this morning with a smile on your face.
我在想今天一定有什么事要发生
I said, Something special's gonna happen today.
假如这小孩有你的头脑和美貌
If this kid has your good looks, your good brains and my good left hook...
和我的左钩拳  他一定很出色
he's really gonna be something.
假如是个女孩呢？是女孩呢
What if it's a boy, I mean, a girl? What if it's a girl?
我还没有想到那一点
I didn't think about that.
她会具有我所没有的
She'll be everything I'm not.
她不会胆怯
She won't have to be shy.
我们可以让她学唱歌和跳舞
We could give her singing and dancing lessons.
每天换一件新衣服怎么样？
How about a new dress every day? Would you like that?
我得请个保镖
I'll hire a bodyguard
当她去上学时可以保护她
when she starts going to school
免受男孩子们的干扰
to keep the boys away.
小男孩们  一般来讲是很讨人厌
You know how them little boys can be a real pest in general, can't they?
假如是男孩的话
And if it's a boy,
我希望跟他爸爸一样
I'd like him to be just like the father.
家里有一头蛮牛还不够吗？
Don't you think one dumbbell in the family's enough, huh?
这孩子将来不会加入任何帮派
I'll tell you one thing. This kid ain't gonna get no tattoos.
他也不到处走走
He ain't gonna be hanging on no corners or dress like no wise guy like me...
他会像你一样出色
He's gonna be a good somebody like you.
像你
Like you.
不  不  像你
No, like you.
- 像你  - 不 像你
- Like you.  - No, like you.
像你
Like you.
艾黛丽安
Adrian,
我们办到了  不是吗？
we did it, didn't we?
你觉得如何  洛奇？
How you feel, Rocky?
我觉得很好
Pretty good.
我们没有早点找你来
The reason we didn't call you a couple of months ago is
因为你的脸那时还肿着
we wanted to wait till the swelling went down.
我知道
I see.
你现在看起来好极了
But you look terrific now.
我们就要大挣一笔钱了很好
We're gonna make a buck together. Don't worry about it.
我跟司马特笛玩具公司签了约
I got a deal from Smart Deal Toy Company.
听过这家公司吗？
Did you ever hear of 'em?
你听说过吗？没有
Maybe Mrs. Rocky did. Did you ever hear of a Smart Deal toy?
没有吗  他们是一流的公司
Big. They're Number One.
他们想作洛奇娃娃
And they wanna make a Rocky doll.
可以弄着玩  也可以打它
You can kick it. You can beat it.
怎么玩都行  给孩子的
It does everything. For kids.
一定很流行
It takes a terrific beating.
我们将会因它而挣一大笔钱
We're gonna make a lot of money with it, okay?
他化好妆了吗？
Is he ready, dear?
好了
Finito.
你看我怎么样？好极了
How do I look? The best.
简直棒透了
Fabulous.
艾黛丽安  你看我怎么样？很奇怪
Adrian, how do I look? Different.
太妙了  我们开始吧  好
Sensational. Come on, let's get it on.
他会很棒的
He's gonna be great.
别紧张
Don't be nervous.
我看起来很呆  是不是？
I look stupid, don't I?
是的
Yes.
有没有防臭剂？没有
You got any deodorant? No.
对不起
Excuse me
好  我们开始  亚瑟
All right. We're ready. Let's go, Arthur.
到笼子里去  洛奇
In the cage, Rocky.
就照我们所预演的
Just the way we rehearsed.
全体预备了
Everyone, get ready for picture now.
小姐们  快点  装得活泼点
Come on, Rocky, we're running late. Girls, come on. Look alive, dear.
亲爱的  来  拿高一点
Could I have it a little higher?
对了
That's it.
魔术时间  活一点
Magic time.
请转  速度
Roll, please. Speed.
动物修毛后  第一次
Beast After-Shave, Take One.
动作
Action.
现在开始吗？
Go now?
开始！
Action!
早晨  我喷了一点
In the morning, I splash it on
结果我闻到.
and it makes me smeal mainly.
我闻到？停！
Smeal mainly? Cut!
应该是有男人气味？
Isn't that "smell manly"?
你认不认得这个字？洛奇
Can you read that, Rocky?
会  我们再来一遍
So, let's go again.
对不起  再来一次
Well, excuse me.
我知道我读错了
You know, I know I said it wrong,
不过  这实在没有男人气味
but it really don't smell manly.
这东西有男人味吗？
I mean, do you think this stuff smelIs like a man?
我认为一点都没有
I say absolutely no.
你讲完了没有？抱歉
Are you finished? I am Sorry
好  再一次  安静
Okay, rolling again. Nice and quiet.
动物修毛后  第二次
"Beast After-Shave" Take Two.
动作
Action
早上…
In the morning,
我喷上了一点
I splash it on
我脸四周全是那类东西
and it surrounds my face with class.
停！
Cut!
动作
Action
野兽刮过脸
Beast After-Shave
使得女人都变成野兽
will turn the women into beasts.
停！
Cut!
动作
Action
你假如想作野兽之王
If you want to be the king of the beasts
带有森林鼠的气味
and smell like a jungle rat
是猫  有点像
That's right. It's "cat." They look alike.
开始！
Action!
下午  我喷上一点
In the afternoon, when I put it on
壮着胆子  外出去约会
to go out with the guys and have a rendez-vous
停！我们换另外一种位置
Cut! We're going to the alternate set.We're cutting the set.
我可以纠正的
I can get it.
我相信  你离开那笼子好吗？
I'm sure you can. Will you get out of the cage?
约会这个字
The word, "rendez-vous"
洛奇  你如果不介意的话
Rocky, if you don't mind.
到别的位置去约会吧
Yes, rendez-vous over to the other set,
我们只浪费了四个小时而已
We've only wasted four hours.
阿瑟  把这边整理一下  我们重新组合
Arthur, will you organize here? We're going to the alternate set.
起先看起来是不错  事实倒不然
It sounded great before it came out like that.
要女郎换另外服装
Get the damn club away from him and get the girIs into their other outfits.
管服装的人呢？
Where are the wardrobe people? Where are the prop people?
好了  把他弄湿！
All right, wet him down!
亚瑟  请出来
Arthur, step out, please.
速度
Speed.
动物修毛后争斗  第七次
"Beast After-Shave, the contender," Take Seven.
想办法演好  开始！
Try to get it right. Action!
我叫洛奇·巴尔博亚意大利种马
Hi, my name is Rocky Balboa, the ltalian Stallion.
有人说我是美国之梦
They say I'm the American Dream
不过不是因为
but not because
我能再演一次吗？
Can I do it over again?
老天！停！
Christ! Cut!
不  继续拍
No, just keep it rolling.
只要读读提词卡就好了
Just, read it off the dummy cards.
提词卡？请继续下去
Dummy cards? Please, go on.
等等  我要解释一下
Wait a minute. I'd like to explain something.
我不是紧张  我只是像你说话  头脑不灵光散散的人
You know, I ain't punchy. I got what you call a relaxed brain
就像我在这里所讲的一样
but I ain't punchy, you know. It's just the way I talk here.
那有什么差别？
What's the difference?
就照上面所写的去作就可以？
Can you just do it the way it's written?
这根本就不对  知道吗？
This whole thing here ain't right.
怎么样才是对的呢？
What isn't right?
你没礼貌
You're a rude guy.
我很努力  你却对我凶
I'm trying very hard and you're being rude.
我太太觉得难堪  对不对？艾黛丽安
That's bad manners, ain't it, Adrian?
是的
Yes.
就是真的被打  我也不想要这东西
But I'll tell ya, I gotta be almost punchy to be
留在我脸上
doing this in front of my wife.
你不想干吗？那就别干！走人！
You wanna quit? Then quit! Leave!
滚蛋！我一开始就不要你！
Get outta here! I didn't want you for this setup in the first place!
你浪费  浪费了我们的时间
You have wasted, wasted our time, sir.
真是一个很恼人的下午
This is a complete bust.
蓝诺  你要上哪？
Leonard, where are you going?
带他走  把他带走
l want you to take him with you, Leonard. Take this man with you.
他没有经验  我只和内行人共事
He is not a professional. I only work with professionals.
就因为你不识字
You cost us thousands of dollars
所以害了我们花了几千元！
because you can't read!
那贼咆哮地说
snarled the robber.
没有时间可骂咒我
It's no time to cuss me,
伙伴们  拿起步枪找掩护
By God! Fellas, grab your rifles an' take color cover.
听起来怎么样？
How's it sound?
还不错
It's good.
是吗？能读得好就可以去找个
You know, being a good reader's gonna help me get
文书方面的好差事
a good office job, you know.
还要不要听？
Wanna hear some more?
我都等不及了  好的
I can't wait. OK.
没有掩护的地方
There ain't no cover, Smokey
我们最好到峡谷去
We better head for the canyon.
你读得很好
You read nice.
谢谢你  你很会讲话  谢谢
Thank you. You lie nice.
你中学读到几年级  包波亚先生？
And how far did you go in high school?
9年级
Ninth.
现在  最后一个问题
Now, one last question.
你有没有过前科？
Do you have a criminal record?
没什么好说的
Nothing worth bragging about.
你对于劳力工作有没有兴趣？
Would you be interested in some sort of manual labor?
我不反对实在的劳力工作
I got nothing against honest manual labor.
我比较喜欢向你一样坐着上班
It's just that I'dlike to see if I could make a living sitting down like you're doing over there.
我老实说
Can I be honest?
没有人会让你作文书的工作
No one's going to offer you an office job.
竞争太厉害了
There's too much competition.
你为什么不去比赛拳击？
Why don't you fight?
报纸上说你是个很棒的拳手
I read you're a very good fighter.
是吗？
Yeah? Well...
一个晚上脸被人打 500 下
Was you ever punched in the face 500 times a night?
日子长了  受不了
Stings after a while, you know.
非常感谢你抽空见我
Thank you very much for your time. I appreciate it.
包波亚先生？是的
Mr. Balboa, Yeah.
抱歉  我们没有空位
I'm very sorry. We have nothing.
真的吗？下一个
Are you sure? Next
现实点  你没有高中证明不合格
Look, pal, you gotta be realistic. You got no high-school diploma no qualifications.
你难道不会对一份待遇佳的
Wouldn't you be more content
苦力工作感到更满意吗？
with a good-paying menial labor job?
我要的话可得到其他工作
The way I see it is I can get another job if I wanna.
我想做很不开心的事吗？
But do I wanna? Do I wanna be doing something I ain't gonna be happy doing?
我们现在需要钱
Plus, you know, we need the money now, Butkus.
狗不会了解我的困难  过来点
Dogs don't wanna hear my problems. Come on.
有时候我还真希望我是狗
I wish I was a canine sometimes.
来亲我一下
Give me a kiss.
唯一的工作是搬运牛肉
The only job I got's lugging beef.
没有更好的职位吗？
You have nothin' better for Rocky than hauling beef?
就这么办  洛奇  假如你要工作
That's all I got,and we're cutting back,too.if you want to work,
就要一周一周算钱  可以吗？
it'll be from week to week, okay?
好呀  我什么时候可开始上班？
That's okay with me, but when can I start?
明天如何？
How about tomorrow?
今天好吗？
How about today?
好呀  今天货刚到  太好了
Okay, we got a load coming in. Great.
保利  你好像瘦了！
Paulie, you look kinda skinny there!
瘦了不少  啊？
He's losing weight, ain't he?
别想法子来谢我
Don't bother to thank me.
多谢你
Thanks a lot, Paulie.
你也不必为手表来谢我
And, you don't have to thank me for the watch either.
你是我今天里看到最顺眼的事物
There's the best-looking thing I've seen all day.
你看起来累极了
You look tired.
不  我的脸看起来有倦容
No, my face is tired.
但我觉得还好
I feel okay.
要不要去洗个澡？
Do you want to take a hot bath?
不要  我觉得精力充足
No, come on. I feel dynamic, honest.
听着  明天…
Listen, tomorrow...
我下班以后
I was thinking at work maybe after work
我带你出去吃饭
I'll take you out.
你要不要玩一玩？
You wanna do something nice, huh? You want to do that?
你的肚子怎么样了？很好
How's your stomach? Fine.
你看起来很好  你知道吗？
You look great. You know that?
但是你看起来累了
You look tired, though.
他们好像是老朋友了  不是吗？
they're just like old friends, ain't they?
是呀  老朋友从没有这么有意思
Old friends never tasted this good.
我听过这种话！
I heard that!
你
You
你  洛奇
You Rocky
你找我吗？法蓝克
You wanted me, Frank?
洛奇  我不得不解雇你
Roky, I gotta let you go.
怎么回事？我很卖力
How come? I'm working hard.
我作得不错呀
I'm doing good.
你是不错
Real good,
但我们得裁员
but we gotta cut back on manpower.
而你才来上班不久
You ain't got enough time in.
年资问题
It's seniority.
假如我自动减薪怎么样？
How about if I take a cut in pay, all right?
没办法  这是工会的规定
Can't do it. Union rules.
规定
Rules, rules.
我今天作完可以吗？
Can I finish out the day?
当然  洛奇  我觉得很遗憾
Sure. Rocky, I'm sorry.
是的  我也是
Me, too.
你的故事能写小说了
You got more stories than a book, you know that?
我妹夫洛奇来了  给我五块钱！
There's my brother-in-law, Rocky. Give me the five!
妹夫来探班了
My brother-in-law came to visit me.
你的工作怎么样？好吧？
How are you? How you doing?
看看你的老家？
Looking over your old stomping ground?
要不要买这部车？
Paulie, you wanna buy this car?
我以为你会喜欢
I thought you liked it.
我用不上了
It's okay, I don't need it no more.
我的眼不好  右转常有困难
I have a hard time making these right turns with my bad eye.
我老是撞到垃圾桶之类的东西
I keep hitting trash cans and things like that.
有家庭问题吗？需要帮忙吗？
You got problems at home? Need bread?
没有  一切都很好
Everything's okay.
这部车很适合你用
You know, this car'd look great wrapped around you, you know.
假如你需要救济的话我可帮你
Look, if you need a handout, I'll give you a handout.
不  我不要救济品
I don't need no handout, Paulie.
你要不要买这部车？
Look, you wanna buy the car?
好啊
Sure.
你怎么不聪明点再去比赛拳击？
Rocky, why don't you be smart and fight again?
我再也不要去比赛拳击
That's okay, I don't need to fight no more.
你要不要买部车？
Listen, you wanna buy the car?
并且立刻付款？
You wanna pick up the payments?
我的妹妹是不是找你的麻烦？
My sister giving you a hard time?
假如是的话  我要打断她的牙齿
You know, if she is, you break her teeth.
我喜欢她的牙齿  你知道的
I appreciate the advice,Paulie,but I kinda like her teeth where they are.
你自己买部车吧
Here ya go, you bought yourseIf a car.
那是一部好车
It's a good car, you know.
为了安全你得扣上安全带
You gotta buckle up for safety and all that.
你要上那儿去？要搭便吗？
Where you going? You need a lift?
回头见
See you around.
嗨  替我向我的老妹问好
Say hi to my sister for me.
你们假如需要车子  尽管说吧！
Listen, if you two need the car, just ask!
我以为你在上班  何时回家的？
When did you get home? I thought you were at work.
不
No,
我不再去上班
I ain't at work no more. I got...
我今天被解雇了
I got canned today.
怎么回事？不知道
What happened? I don't know.
他们正在裁员  那是经济问题
It was nobody's fault.They were just cutting back.You know,it was economics.
你打算怎么办？不知道
What're you gonna do? I don't know.
我在想拳击比赛
I was thinking about fighting.
你的眼怎么办？
What about your eye?
医生说过你再也不能比赛拳击了
The doctor said you shouldn't fight anymore.
不  他建议我不要比拳
He recommended I don't fight,
可是我自己觉得可以
and I recommend that I do.
你会失明的
You can go blind.
没有人会失明的
Nobody's going blind.
真的  我的视力很好
Honest, I see great.
我可以像小猎犬一样好
And I see like a beagle or something like that.
除此之外你想当什么都可以
You could be whatever you wanna be. You don't have to fight anymore.
我是拳手  虽然不大好
You know, I am a fighter. Not too good,
可是那是我的本行
but that's what I do.
洛奇  你答应过不再比拳
Rocky, you gave me your word you wouldn't fight anymore.
假如需要的话  我可以去找事作
I mean, if we need, I could get a job.
你不必那样作
You don't have to do that.
我可以作原来的工作
Oh, sure. I can get my job back,
在猫狗店里兼差
you know, part time, at the pet shop.
不过  应该由我来负担家计
But I'm the one who's supposed to support.
只是短期性
It's just for a little while.
假如你被传染上那一种
Listen, what if you catch some
动物的传染病时  那该怎么办？
pet-shop disease or something?
它们不会生传染病的
There're no pet-shop diseases, Rocky.
真的  我真的想去工作
Really, I wanna work.
你真的那么想吗？
You really wanna do it?
是  我们需要钱
We need the money.
它迟早总是有用的
It'll come in handy.
或许你说得对
Maybe you're right, you know.
你知道怎么做最好
You know what's best.
你能不能准备吃晚饭？我饿了
Darling,could you start dinner? I'm starting to get a little hungry.
不过  我得先完成才行  好吗？
I just wanna finish my workout here, okay?
好的
Sure.
谁呀？
Who the hell is there?!
雅芳的女业务员
Avon lady.
谁呀？洛奇？
Who's that? Rocky?
我不记得给过你钥匙
I don't remember giving you no key.
你看起来没那么不好  对不对？
You don't look so bad, do you, kid?
那是什么？
What's that?
送给我的外太空怪物？
An outer-space monster you brought me?
它叫布可斯  你的耳里塞着什么？
No, that's Butkus, my large dog. What's that in your ear there?
有了这玩意  我可以听得清楚些
What is that? I hear stupid things better.
你是来让我欣赏你的狗吗？
Well now, did you come here to show me that dog?
不  米奇
Mickey,
我可不可以要回我的柜子？
can I have my locker back?
哦  你想干嘛？
Really? What's on your mind?
打拳
Fighting.
打拳？怎么？你想成为瞎子？
Fighting? What? Do you wanna go blind?
- 我不会变成瞎子   - 你没听懂吗？
- Nobody's going blind.  - Now you heard what I said?
我的眼神挺好  没问题
And the eye's great. No problem.
每个拳手都自以为他还有一场好比赛
Listen, every pug thinks he has one good one left.
算了吧  你的拳击生涯已经结束了
Now forget it because your fighting career is over, kid.
- 真的吗？- 我就是这么看的
- Is that right?  - I think that's right.
我拼了半辈子
You know, I spend my whole life getting a career.
才有点成就  你却说都结束了
I get one and you tell me it's over.
这重要吗？
What's the matter?
你把世界拳王打得鼻青脸肿
You shook the hell out of the champion of the whole wide world.
你还不满意吗？
Be happy with that.
或许这次可以表现得更好
Maybe we can do better this time.
或者是一败涂地
Or worse. What about that?
嘿  米奇  我上次帮过你的忙
You, Mick. I've done you a favor last time, you know.
你这次是否可以帮帮我？
Can you do me one this time?
我不知道
I don't know.
你不了解我  我要试试你
You don't understand me. I wanna show you something now. Test you.
现在看看我的鼻尖
Now, you look, right there, at the end of my nose.
我要试你的是看你的鼻尖
I wanna test you. Look at your nose.
我的手指一举起来
Now, when I bring my finger in here,
- 你就告诉我 好吗？- 好
tell me when you see it, will yo?
我看到了
There's the little thing. I see it.
很好
That's good.
我就说过没问题吗？
I told you it was okay.
等等  现在试试另外一只眼
Wait. Now we try the other lamp.
看这边  好  现在告诉我
Now, look here, will you? Now tell me.
我看到了
I see it.
不  你什么也没看到！
No, you see nothing!
克利将会毁了你的脸
Creed would've caved in the whole side of your face.
算了吧  孩子
Now, forget it, kid.
你有决心
You got the heart,
但你已经没有能力了
but you ain't got the tooIs no more.
算了吧！
Now, forget it!
真是这样？
Is that right?
- 还用问吗？-  是吗？
- That is right.  - Yeah?
说不定变成废物的人是你呢？
Maybe it's you who ain't got it no more, you know that?
你甚至连看到的机会都没有
Now look, you didn't even see that coming,
有吗？没有
did you? No.
那是因为有我这样一个  不好的拳击教练
That was from a broken-down pug like me.
你猜拳王会怎样对付你？
What do you think the champ would do to you?
把我打得很惨
I don't know, hurt me bad.
不  他会让你从此完蛋
No, he'd hurt you permanent.
永远地！
Permanent!
假如我不能再参加拳击比赛
if I can't fight no more
那或许我可以在这里帮帮忙
then maybe I can help out around here, you know.
这里？当然可以  不过
Here? Sure, but
你在这里高高在上
You know, you're like royalty here, kid.
你难道想让那些家伙
Do you want those guys to see
看到你提着水桶到处去服侍拳手？
you carrying toweIs and buckets around? Where's your dignity?
我不知道怎么说
I don't know how to say this, you know.
我就是非这样不可
It's just I gotta be around it.
好吧  孩子
All right, kid.
你明天再来好吗？
Will you come back tomorrow, huh?
米奇  谢谢你
Thanks a lot, Mick.
听着
Look,
既然是我在推动这场拳击赛
I don't know about anybody else,but since I'm gonna be promoting the fight myself,
我想要施点压力再重比一次
I want a lot more pressure put on for a rematch.
比赛得前二名都可以获得相同钱
We can get the same money for the two top contenders.
为什么要找包波亚比赛呢？
Why go after Balboa? Why?
因为很多人都认为他赢
Because there's still a lot of people out there that think he won.
骂我说先买通比赛的胜负
There's a lot of people accusing me of having the fight fixed
在学校侮辱我的小孩们
accusing me of being a fake,and insulting my kids at school.
原因就在这里！
That's why!
你想不想知道实情？
You wanna hear the truth?
是的  我是想知道
I wanna hear the truth.
事实上是上回他狗运好
The truth is he was damn lucky.
现在他已经毁了
Now he's all finished.
他六个月来都没事作
I mean, he's been hanging around doing nothing for six months.
任何好的教练绝不会去训练他
And any trainer worth anything wouldn't have nothing to do with him.
我是说
Now I say,
我们再选其他新拳手
Let's go after some new meat.
别去管这无赖
Forget this bum.
你看我是否把他击败了？
Do you think I beat him the last time? Do you?
你自己决定吧
You got the decision.
我是赢了  不过我并没有打败他！
Man, I won, but I didn't beat him!
你怕什么？托尼
What are you afraid of, Tony?
老实说吗？
Honest?
对  老实讲
Yeah, honest.
我们看他没有一个地方顺眼
He's all wrong for us, baby.
你打那家伙  我从来就没有看过
I saw you beat that man
别人像他那样的挨打
like I never saw no man get beat before.
而那家伙却对你紧迫不舍
And the man kept coming after you.
我们的生活中不需要那种人
We don't need that kind of man in our life.
我了解你的感受
I know what you're feeling.
忘了吧！
Let it go!
都忘了吧！你是拳王
Let it go! You're the champ.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你是我的公关经理  对吧？
You're in charge of my public relations, right?
我要全方位展开新宣传
I want a new campaign started.
用舆论压力把他逼出来
I want something done publicly to bring this man out.
想办法让他抬不起头来
I want something done to jar this man's pride.
想办法让他身边的人对他说三道四
I want something done to get the people around him talking.
如果我们采取这种羞辱策略
You realize if we use this humiliation tactic
你等于在说  自己是坏人
you're setting yourself up as the bad guy.
听好  不论用什么手段  只要让他上拳台
Look, man, whatever gets him in the ring.
什么？
What's happening?
你看看吧  什么呢？
What're you talking about?
你听到了  什么事？
You heard me. What is this?
意大利种马
没 种
你不觉得很有趣吗？
It's kinda funny, don't you think?
奇可  听着  你笑什么呢？
Chico, listen. What's with the grin?
什么事这么高兴？听我一句劝
How'd you get so happy with yourself? Let me tell ya something.
学着  咆哮
Snarl more, you see.
圣经上说了  要从气势上压倒对手
Now a good snarl can give you what the Bible calIs a psychological edge.
所以出拳的时候要咆哮
Because ya snarl on your punches.
等等  洛奇！过来
Wait a minute. Rocky! Come here a minute, will you?
教教这个拉丁傻子
Show this Latin lamebrain
怎样边出拳  边咆哮
how to snarl and punch. Show him that.
看到了！
That's it, you see!
就是这样  无比凶残！这就是咆哮
That's ugly! That's a snarl.
约翰  你把这水桶倒一下好吗？
John will ya empty them buckets? They're flowing over. Will you do that?
约翰  让我来
Johnny, I'll do it.
让他来
Let him do it.
我去  没关系  洛奇
I got it, Rocky. Come on, I don't mind.
没关系
It's no problem.
等一下
Wait a minute.
拿走吧
Now you can take it.
你除了会应声以外  没有其他有力一点的吗？
Can't you think of anything tougher to say than "whoops"?
快打呀！
Come on, Chink, hit that right. Bang!
你好吗？托尼
Tony, how you doing?
我好吗？不  应该是问你好吗？
How am I doing? No, how are you doing?
我听说你在这个破地方打工  你到底是怎么想的？
What're ya doing? Give it to me straight.
就是想干点活  挣点钱
You know, sweeping. Making a few bucks here and there.
洛奇  你又不是清洁工  这种活委屈你了
You ain't no janitor, Rocky. You don't need a job like this.
此外  你又是意大利人
Besides, you're ltalian.
这样好了  回来跟我干吧  洛奇
Now you come back and work for me, Rocky.
我能干什么呢？你想让我…
What would I be doing? You mean like...
回去帮你收账？
collecting or something?
你说呢？回来吧  回码头  那儿空气好
What else? You come back, work on the docks, get some fresh air.
这里臭死了
It stinks in here.
托尼  谢谢你的好意  不过…
Tony, I appreciate the offer, but...
我没办法再作那种事
I can't do that stuff no more.
为了健康  嗯？我得走了
It's healthy, huh? Look, I gotta go.
保重  拳王
Take it easy, huh, champ?
回头见
See you around.
记得那家伙吗？洛奇
Remember that guy, Rocky.
店内的各动物可好？
How's everybody in the clubhouse tonight?
很好  你今天过的怎样？
Fine. How'd your day go?
无数的嘲笑  你要不要帮忙？
A million laughs. You know, it was great. You need some help with that?
好的  好
Yes. Yes, ok.
艾黛丽安
You know Adrian,
或许你应该呆在家里  让肚子休息
l was thinking maybe you oughta stay home and rest your stomach.
这只是兼职  再说家里需要钱
Come on, Rocky, it's just part time. We need the money.
或许你对
Well, maybe you're right.
好了
There we go.
不合我的口味  我喜欢麦片
That ain't my brand, huh? I like oatmeal.
我说  今天就干到这儿吧？
Listen, why don't we forget all this work?
现在跟我回家  路上我跟你讲几个笑话  让你好好笑一笑
I'll tell ya a few jokes on the way home and maybe you'll laugh,
生活需要笑声  你说呢？行吗？
We need a few laughs in our life. What do ya think? Maybe?
行
Yes.
应该行  也许吧
Maybe. Okay,
那好  我们就回家  好吗？
let's get outta here, okay?
我们走吧
Here we go.
嘿  艾黛丽安  听这个笑话
Listen, Adrian Listen to this one:
奶牛为什么系铃铛？
Why do cows wear bells?
为什么？
Why?
因为奶牛角不能吹
Because their horns don't work.
那有没有笑死你？没有吧？
Isn't that killing you? No? Huh?
这是我三年级时压箱底的笑话
Everybody liked it in third grade.
所有同学听了都笑
I used to break everybody up with it.
嘿  你是扫地高手
You really sweep good, man.
他在跟你讲话吗？
Is he talking to you?
他一定是认错人了  走吧
He has me mixed up with somebody else. Come on.
意大利小鸡！
Italian chicken!
你们活得挺自在啊
You guys got the easy life.
今天有没有什么变动的？
How you guys doing? Did anybody move today, you know? Huh?
这里的生活好吗？
How's life in the bowl?
你们得时不时运动一下
You gotta exercise once in a while.
吃些点心怎么样？
Would you like a little snack, a little something?
克夫  过来  哈罗  林克.
Come on, Cuff. Hello, Link,
你淹死了吗  嗯？
what are you drowning down there, huh?
想听听电视节目吗  嗯？
You wanna hear some TV, huh?
巴可斯  到这儿来
Come here, Butkus. Come here, boy.
你今天作了什么事？
What'd you do today, huh?
你今天有没有叫？
Did you bark at anybody today?
艾黛丽安
You know, Adrian,
我觉得布可斯是只反常的狗
sometimes I look at Butkus. I don't think he's a normal canine.
你以为它是什么？不知道
What you think he is? I don't know.
只是看起来不像只正常的狗…
He's just don't look like a regular dog sometimes when I look inside there.
我去过阿波罗·奎迪豪华体育馆
Earlier today, I was down at Apollo Creed's palatial gym
就像往常一样
as usual,
世界拳王提起洛奇·巴尔博亚
the world champion was not at a loss for words about Rocky Balboa.
很多人都想要我重新再比赛一次
I know a lot of people wanna see me
跟一位胆小鬼叫意大利种马
in a rematch with a timid fellow who calIs himseIf "The ltalian Stallion."
不过这个人不配跟我在拳场相会
But this man does not have the honor to meet me in the ring.
洛奇退休了
Rocky Balboa did officially retire.
你叫什么名字？
What is your name, huh?
那无赖汉藏起来了
The bum's hiding. The bum's running.
他不敢面对我  他害怕
He doesn't wanna face me. He's scared.
自从那次不一致的判决获胜之后
You've been under close scrutiny ever since that split-decision victory.
经过仔细的考虑
I think there's more here than meets the eye.
一些记者们  包括我在内.
A lot of reporters, including me,
都认为应该是平手
thought it was an even draw.
那是你的看法
That's your opinion, you're entitled to it.
不过我现在已经准备好重赛
But now I'm ready to have a rematch
来证明这幸运的拳手
to prove that this lucky club-fighter, that's what he is
并没有什么技术
does not have the skill
能跟我这样一位优秀的运动员
to last five minutes
在拳场比赛五分钟以上
in the ring with a superior athlete like me.
那个人不愿面对我
The man's running. The man's hiding. The man doesn't wanna face me.
所以  无论你是叫洛奇·巴尔博亚
So I say to you, Rocky Balboa,
或其他的名字
or whatever your name is
我要让美国人和全世界的人知道
that I want the American people to know I want the whole world to know
我随时准备好向你挑战
that I'm ready,willing and able to meet you anywhere,anyplace,anytime.
我将把所谓的拳击斗士
I'll meet and defeat this so-called fighter...
自封为意大利种马的人击倒
who calIs himseIf "The ltalian Stallion."
假如他有胆量的话
If the man only has the guts to give me a call.
他可以打电话给我  我付帐！
And you can call me collect. Call me, Balboa!
拳手付挨拳者
This would be a legitimate rematch the boxer against the puncher,
我相信每个人都希望看到他们
and I think everyone wants to see them
重返拳场比赛
back in the ring together.
不过  只有一个问题
But there's only one problem:
洛奇·巴尔博亚在那里？
Where is Rocky Balboa?
不是什么好东西！
No-good bum!
我在想  我不应该去作广告
You know, I was thinking that I ain't supposed to do no commercials
而且  我也不应该去肉店上班
and I ain't supposed to work in no meat house.
我应该去打拳
I'm supposed to be a fighter.
我以为你已经不再比拳了
I thought you gave that up.
我又变得默默无闻
I think I'm becoming a nobody again, too.
在谁的眼里？我可不这么想
In whose eye? Not mine.
在我的脑子里  这里
In mine. In here.
我们会渡过的只是
We'll get by.That's just it.
我不愿意艰苦过活  你知道吗？
I don't want just to get by the hard way, you know?
我要你用好的
I want you to have good things.
我要小孩子也用好的
I want the kid to have good things.
我们总会有的
We'll have them.
我认为现在就需要  不是吗？
I just think we need them now. Don't you?
洛奇  求求你
Rocky, please.
洛奇  你用不着证明什么
You don't have to prove anything.
艾黛丽安  我就只懂这个
Adrian, it's all I know.
我不要你去
I don't want you to do it.
我就只懂这个
It's all I know.
艾黛丽安
Adrian
你知道的
You know
我从来没有要求过你
I never asked you
请别让我当个女人
to stop being a woman, you know.
拜托
please.
我求你
I'm asking you, please.
不要叫我别作男人  拜托
Don't ask me to stop being a man.
我想我们得把他除掉
I think we oughta knock his block off.
那当然
Absolutely.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们就这做吧
Let's do it.
阿波罗
Apollo,
是不是重赛的地点已经选好？
has a site been chosen for the rematch?
在费城的史贝川
This fight will be held in the Philadelphia Spectrum.
我要让他的老乡来看这场比赛
Because I want this man's home town to see this.
我要所有费城的人  所有美国人
I want all of Philadelphia. I want all of America,
及全世界的人来看我
I want the whole world
我要在二个回合内就把他击倒
to see me destroy this man after two short rounds.
我要把他所剩余的躯体
Because after this fight,he's gonna have to donate what's gonna be left of his body to science.
作科学用途  我保证
But there won't be much. That, I can guarantee.
你对史贝川拳赛有何感想？
what do you think about the fight taking place in the Spectrum?
我觉得很高兴为什么？
I'm very happy about that.Why?
离我家只有十分钟的路
It's only about 10 minutes from my house.
我听说你头一次比赛败在左拳之下
A lot of people say you lost the fight, a victim of the Southpaw Jinx.
你会怕左拳手吗？
Did fighting a left-hander throw you off?
左拳手没有什么了不起！
Southpaw Jinx nothing!
我上回出手太轻了  算他好运
Last time,I took the fight too lightly and this man was just plain lucky.
不过这一次  你们就会看到.
But this time, you all will see
真正的阿波罗·奎迪
the real Apollo Creed.
闪电般的快速  让你无法招架
The world's gonna see the real Apollo. Lightning fast and hard to catch.
不是玩玩的  而是真的比划
No playing, no jiving. Just business.
洛奇
Rocky,
你这次对抗阿波罗可有胜算？
do you think you have a chance this time against Apollo?
我也不知道  他看起来很生气
I don't know. He looks pretty mad.
我跟米奇  我们会尽力就是
Me and Mick, we're gonna try our best.
只要他还能打
His lungs he's gonna punch out.
他是谁？ 阿尔·卡彭吗？阿尔·卡彭也成为20世纪20~30年代最有影响力的黑手党领导人
Now who's that, Al Capone?"疤脸"的绰号
他是谁？阿尔·卡彭吗？
Now who's that, Al Capone?
我才懒的理你
I wouldn't sweat you.
可能有很多人不喜欢我
A lot of people may not like me and that's okay.
不过没关系  但是在十一月
But come November,
阿波罗·奎迪会提供最大的感恩节奇观
Apollo Creed will provide the ultimate gala spectacle on Thanksgiving,
在他的众乡亲之前
in front of this man's home crowd
我要像革除坏习惯一样的除掉他
I'm gonna drop him like a bad habit.
洛奇  这场比赛的佣金很可观
Rocky, your pay for the fight is very substantial.
- 你打算怎么花这笔钱？- 对 怎么花？
- What're you gonna do with the money?  - Yes, what're you gonna do?
我要做的第一件事  是交房租
First thing I gotta do is, I gotta pay the rent, you know.
还有  我来的路上列了一张单子  想了一些要做的事
Then,I made this list on the way over and I was just thinking of things to do.
我想买几顶帽子  买辆摩托车
I'd like to get a couple of hats, a motorcycle and
给艾黛丽安买几瓶香水
a couple of quarts of perfume, for Adrian.
她喜欢香喷喷的
She likes to smell good.
然后买点玩具  比如安尼和大鸟
And some Muppet toys, you know. Ernie and Big Bird
还有那只青蛙  叫什么  可米特？
and that frog. What's his name, Kermit?
我还要送给教堂一座雕像
I thought maybe a statue for the Church and
给保利买个刨冰机  你喜欢刨冰  不是吗？
I think a snow-cone machine for you, Paulie.You like snow cones,don't you?
洛奇  你想不想回敬拳王几句？
Rocky, got anything derogatory to say about the champ?
回敬？对  他很棒
Derogatory? Yeah, he's great.
扮个小丑吧  阿波罗？
How about some clowning shots, Apollo?
你看这里像马戏团吗？
Does this look like a circus to you, man?!
十一月见  你是我的
Come November, you're mine.
他很生气
He's very upset.
看出他怎样出手打你的眼吗？
See how he bumps that jab into your eye?
有
Yeah.
你有勇气重回拳场跟他较量
You got guts to go back in the ring with him, kid.
谢谢
Thanks a lot, Mick.
你的招式很容易看出来
Your style's too easy to figure out.
左拳手是最不好的
Left-handed fighters, they're the worst.
多半都会打到脸.
They lead with their face mostly,
非得改掉那致命的左拳
gotta throw that big left.
规定一点也不好
The right's no damn good.
他们应该禁止用左拳比赛
They oughta outlaw southpaws.
你为什么以前都不告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me this before?
我不想伤你的心  现在看
I didn't wanna hurt your feelings. Now, look
你得创造奇绩  必须改掉旧习
You gotta pull this miracle off. You gotta change everything.
你得学用右拳
You gotta learn to be a right-handed fighter.
这样会让阿波罗弄不清楚
Now, this'll confuse Apollo
怎么回事  也可乘机保护眼
and it'll protect that bad eye.
我再也没办法学用右拳
No, I can't learn how to fight right-handed no more.
什么叫不能  没有不能的事情！
What's can't? There ain't no can'ts! There's no can'ts!
他会把你打得比现在还要  惨
Now he will beat you uglier than you are now.
开始练右拳
Now listen, you start fighting right-handed
而你在突然之间改变拳路
and then ya change sudden
可以重写拳史
and that'll make history.
不过我们首先要练速度.
But first, we gotta get speed,
飞快的速度
demon speed.
我们要敏捷  快速
Speed's what we need.
我要你看看！
We need greasy, fast speed!
鸡是怎样用它的二条腿来跑的
Now, I show you a trick how to get some speed in them legs.
为什么要穿那件发臭的汗衣？
You have to wear that stinking sweatshirt?
它可以给我带来好运
It brings me luck, you know.
那会招惹苍蝇的
You know what it brings? It brings flies.
现在听我说！
Now listen, I want ya to try Listen to me!
我要你试着去追这只小鸡
I want you to try to chase this little chicken.
为什么要追小鸡？真难为情
Why do I gotta chase a chicken for? It's embarrassing, you know.
因为我说要就是要
First, because I said so.
追鸡这个项目
And second, because chicken-chasing
我们常常用来当作一种训练
is how we always used to train in the old days.
你要是追的上它  你可比美光速
You catch this thing, you can catch greased lightning.
我宁愿吃也不愿意去追它
I'd rather eat it than chase it.
看起来的好像不够成熟.
It ain't mature, but all right.
你也一样不成熟  去追吧！
Neither are you very mature!
我是拳手  不是农夫
I'm a fighter. I ain't a farmer.
快！快抓它！
Come on at it! Go on and get him!
抓它  抓它！
Get him, get him!
你是怎么搞的？快抓呀！
What's the matter with you? Get him!
快！你怎么了？抓住它！
Come on! What's the matter with you? Get him!
抓起来！抓起来！
Pick him up! Pick him up!
抓住它！
Pull him around!
你瞎转悠什么？速度  速度
What's the matter? You're so fast.
你站住啦？速度！
Are your standards still speed, speed!?
连只小鸡都抓不到  呵？
Can't you catch a little chicken?
快动呀  动呀！
Come on, run!
别停下来！
Move your tail!
你是怎么弄的？像个女人
You look like a girl out there.
我觉得像是肯塔基来的呆子
I feel like a Kentucky-fried idiot.
醒醒好吗？醒醒  快呀  打呀
Wake up, will you? Will you wake up?
喂  洛奇  我妹妹是怎么回事？
What's the matter with my sister?
艾黛丽安不喜欢我去比拳
Adrian don't like this.
她又哭又闹
She started crying and everything.
他不喜欢我们打拳
She don't like me fighting no more.
怎么唠起家常了  办正经事好吗？
What's with this domestic stuff?!
打刺拳  打到手疼！
Jab that till it hurts!
连续打五百下  不行停
Five hundred times without stopping.
听见了吗？别停下  五百下！
Do you hear me?! Five hundred times.
米奇  我想用另外一只手
Mick, I wanna use my other arm.
你敢用  我就把它砍掉  明白了吗？
If you do, I'm gonna chop it off. Is that clear?
我想想办法
I'll figure something.
我只能全靠你了
I wish you would. I'd appreciate it, you know.
对不起  你讲完了没有？
I'm sorry, are you finished?
我们可以开始了吗？
Can we go to work?
现在出手去打击那个沙包
That would be nice. Now hit that bag.
打到手痛为止！
Jab it till it hurts. Go ahead!
三  四
Three...four....
要用力击五百下！打！
Now I want 500 high ones! Go!
多少了  七或八？
Where was I, seven or eight?
五  六
Five, six.
一  二  一  二  快点
One, two. One, two. Come on,
打翻它  快！
turn it over. Come on, stab it, stab it. Come on!
打！打！速度！速度！
Hit it! Come on! Speed! Speed! Speed!
好  加快！
All right, pick it up!
快点！快点！
Faster! Faster!
快点！
Faster!
快呀！
Come on! Faster!
停！
Time!
嘿  来呀！
Leave me alone!
起来！
Get up!
再给我找一个  行吗？
Get me another one, all right?
好了  让这些陪练喘口气
Come on, you gotta ease up on these sparring partners.
你去叫另一个来
You just get me another man.
慢下来了  怎么了？
What's the matter?
那布袋跳得太快了吗？
That bag's too fast for you?
他们讲话太无礼了
They gonna pound that sass right out of him.
我们上回就应该赢的
Last time, we should've won,
不过  你这一次会令人感到震惊
but this time you're gonna be scary, kid.
你会变成快速敏捷的意大利怪物！
You're gonna be a greasy, fast, ltalian monster!
你就要可以削雷  吞闪电了！
You're gonna eat lightnin'. You're gonna crap thunder!
我们得把你关在笼子里  孩子
We're gonna have to put you in a cage, kid.
我们休息一下好吗？
Let's take a break, Mick, all right?
休息什么？还没练完呢
Break? What break?
你到底要去那里？还没完呢
Where you going? We're not finished.
嘿  你要去哪？我在自言自语
I said, where the hell you going?! Talking to myself, mister.
加速  加速！
Speed! Speed!
逮住那混蛋！
Catch that punk!
快！快！
Speed, damn it! Speed!
你难道对付不了那小鬼？
Can't you catch that little squirt?
你不能吗？
Can't you?!
快点！打倒他！
Come on! Get the lead out!
加油！加油！
Move! Move! Fast!
打倒他
You look dead.
如果你追得过那小滚球
If you're gonna catch that little speedball
就可以击败奎迪
you're gonna catch Creed easy.
快呀  快！
Come on! Move, move!
暂停！
Time!
笨蛋  过来！
Dead-ass, get over here!
你病了吗？孩子
You sick, kid?
怎么回事？
What's the matter with you?
没事
Nothing.
你听好  孩子
Let me tell you something, kid.
现在如果比赛45分钟
Now, for a 45-minute fight
你就得苦练四万五千分钟
you gotta train hard for Forty-five thousand minutes.
那就是十个星期
That's 10 weeks.
一天要练十小时  听好！
That's 10 hours a day, you listening?!
在听吗  你一天都还练不到呢！
You ain't even trained one! I don't know
等什么？你在等什么？什么呢？
what the hell you're waiting for.
不知道
I don't know
随你便吧
Suit yourself.
嘿  洛奇
Rocky.
保利  你近来好吗？
Paulie, how you doing?
我在担心你  我一直看你
I'm worried about you. I been watching.
- 怎么了？- 你的精神不太好
- What?  - Your head ain't screwed on right.
哦  得了  我挺好的
Come on. I'm doing okay. You know,
我一直在想  你来做我的助手吧？
I've been thinking if you'd like to work my corner.
可以参与这场比赛
You wanna get involved in this fight?
参与什么？看着你被打死？
Get involved in what? Watching you get murdered?
别这样  我打得挺好
Come on, I'm doing okay.
我妹妹嫁你真不好
My sister got you so guilty
他逼得你团团转
you're running all over the place.
没什么
No, it ain't all right.
嘿  保利  没事的  好吗？
Paulie, it's okay. All right?
不好
It's not okay.
别去烦艾黛丽安  好吗？
You just leave Adrian alone, all right?
嘿  孩子  带上这个
Hey kid, carry this will ya?
你提痰桶的样子  更让我喜欢！
Because I liked ya better when ya was carrying spit!
你这话什么意思？
What's that supposed to mean?
我好像在训练一个应该
It means that you're training like a ninth-grade pug
在某处加油站学加油的中学生
who oughta be pumping gas in Jersey someplace.
- 是吗？- 就是这意思
- Yeah?  - That's what it means.
米奇  我要去洗个澡
I think I wanna go take a shower, Mick.
洗洗你的脑袋  洗明白了
Soak your head someplace. Soak it good.
- 艾黛丽安 你在哪？- 保利
- Adrian, where are you?  - Paulie.
对  你要干嘛？
What the hell are ya doing?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
- 你要干嘛？- 什么干嘛？
- What are you doing?  - About what?
你干嘛让那小子那么难过？
About messing up that guy over there.
别教训我  我只是想让他安全
I'm just trying to keep him safe.
是吗  喂松鼠就能保证他安全？
What, feeding these goddamn squirrels?
我这样教你的吗？
Did I teach ya how to do that
当他需要你的协助时？
while you're ditching the guy when he needs your help?
而我耳朵听到的是这样吗？
I can't believe my ears.
你什么都没有教我
You didn't teach me anything.
我从来没有伤过洛奇的心
And I never hurt Rocky.
你让他心里很难过  知道吗？
You're messing up his brain real bad. Do you know that?
我没有  我不知道你在说什么
That's not what I'm doing. I don't know what you're talking about.
别那样说对我说！
Don't tell me!
他会因为你而受伤的
He's gonna get hurt because of you.
不要那样说  那不是真的！
It ain't true. Don't say that!
这是事实
I'm saying it.
你去告诉他没有关系
Come across and tell him it's all right.
不好  保利！
It's not all right, Paulie!
假如他瞎了  你就可以不管
If he goes blind, you walk away.
我作不到  我爱他  你不同！
I can't. I love him, you don't!
你怎么呢？
What're you doing?
你怎么呢？到底那边不好
What're you doing? What's wrong?
艾黛丽安  你是怎么搞的？
Adrian, what's the matter?
来吧  你的勇气呢？
Come on, where're your guts?
你有什么问题  米奇？
What's your problem, Mick?
我的问题？是你有问题
My problem? You got a problem, kid.
心理问题
You got a ticker problem.
你的脑袋一片空白吗？
What's the matter? You got nothing left inside, huh?
你训练时就像个懒汉  你知道吗？
Because you're training like a damn bum. You know that?
懒汉？
A bum?
懒汉！
A bum!
也许你是对的  也许我就是不行
Maybe you're right. Maybe I ain't got it no more.
好啊  那你就别别浪费我的时间了  听见了吗？
Then don't you waste my time no more, do you hear that?
滚吧！
Go away!
滚到你那个码头吧
Go back to the docks where you belong.
回去当你的无名小卒！
You'll go back to being a two-bit nothing!
而且  你再也不要来找我
But don't you ever come back here again
因为我已经太老了
because I'm too old
没有多余的时间可以浪费
to waste my time
去训练一个像你这样的一个
trying to train a no-good loser like you.
输不起的懒汉！
You bum!
洛奇  街对面有人找你
They want you across the street.
你太太病了
You're wife's sick.
巴尔博亚先生  我是库伯医生
Mr. Balboa, I'm Dr. Cooper.
虽然早产一个月  但是婴儿很健康
The baby is fine even though it's a month premature.
男孩  女孩？
What is it?
是个男孩
It's a boy.
我没想到她居然生了
Holy smoke, I didn't know she could do it.
艾黛丽安怎么样了？她在那里？
How's Adrian? Where is Adrian?
她得了并发症
She's had complications.
什么意思？
Like what?
你太太大量出血
Your wife was hemorrhaging
她到医院来的时候
when she was brought in.
因为紧张或者疲劳过度而早产
The premature delivery was most likely caused by straining or overwork.
突然失血造成昏迷不醒
And the sudden loss of blood has caused her to slip into a coma.
艾黛丽安  是我
Adrian, it's me.
他们说  你病得很重  不过
They said you're very sick, but
我不相信
I don't wanna believe that.
或许你只是劳累而已
Maybe you're just tired, you know.
别担心  尽量睡好吗？
Don't worry about nothing. You just sleep as long as ya want, okay?
我会留在这里等你醒
Because I'm gonna be here when ya wake up.
洛奇  算了吧
Rocky, come on.
留在这里也没用
You're not doing any good, you know.
倒不如去看看小孩子
Let's go see the kid. That's what Adrian would want.
不  我要跟艾黛丽安一起去看他
No, we gotta see him together.
没关系  我们要一起去看他
We gotta see him together.
巴尔博亚先生
Mr. Balboa
探访时间已过
visiting hours are over.
我不能留下吗？我不出声的
Well, can't I stay? I'll be quiet.
很抱歉  这是医院的规定
I'm sorry. Hospital rules.
我在旁边也不会作什么
I can't do any more of this watchin' stuff.
你们有没有教堂？
Do you have a chapel?
有的
Yes, we do.
晚安
Good night.
嘿  洛奇
Hi, Rocky.
现在是凌晨三点
It's three in the morning.
你可知道我  去过你家.
You know that I went up to your house.
他们告诉我  你在这里
They told me you was here.
现在是凌晨三点  孩子
It's 3:00 a.m., kid.
艾黛丽安  是个好女孩
Adrian she's a good girl.
我对你们二人感到遗憾
You know, I'm sorry for both of you.
我帮不上忙  是吗？
There's nothing I can do, is there?
只是
Except
我一旦说了…
I'd like to tell you something once,
我以后就不会再讲了
and then I ain't gonna say it again.
洛奇  你又有  另一次机会
Rock, you got another shot.
这是第二次机会
It's the second shot
去挑战世界冠军
the biggest title in the world.
而你要去交赛…
And you're gonna be swapping punches
和世上最危险的拳手比赛
with the most dangerous fighter in the world.
假如
And just in case...
你的脑筋不太清楚.
you know, your brain ain't working so good
这些很快就要面临到的
all this happens pretty soon.
而你若没有准备好
And you ain't ready.
你一定会面目全非
You're nowhere near in shape.
所以  我说  看在上帝的份上
So I said, for God's sake.
你为什么不坚强起来
Why don't you stand up
奋力去迎战这家伙
and fight this guy hard
就像你以前一样？那次太棒了！
like ya done before?! That was beautiful!
可不要像这样躺在他面前！
But don't sit down in front of him like this!
像个呆子一样
Like, I don't know, some kind of mongrel or something.
否则他会把你的脸打碎！
Because he's gonna kick your face in pieces!
这家伙不想赢  他只想侮辱你
This guy just don't wanna win. He wants to bury you.
他要向全世界证明
He wants to humiliate you. He wants to prove to the whole world
那不算什么
that it was nothing
只是个首次出现的怪人！
but some kind of a freak the first time out!
他也说过你只不过是
And he said you're
有一次运气好的无赖罢了！
a one-time lucky bum!
我不
I don't
我不想在一个
I don't want to get mad
像这样神圣的场所发火…
in a BiblicaI place like this.
而且我认为你并不只这样  孩子！
But I think you're a hell of a lot more than that, kid!
不过  你要是把这件事弄坏了
But if you want to blow it.
你想把它弄砸
If you want to blow this thing
该死  我跟你一致行动
damn it, I'm gonna blow it with you.
你假如要留在这里
If you wanna stay here, I'll stay with you.
我就跟你留在这里
I'll stay with you.
我跟你留在这里
我留下来祈祷  对我有何损失？
I'll stay and pray. What I got to lose?
就会好的
It's gonna be okay.
没有别的路通农场了
There ain't no other traiI to the ranch,
也没捷径
or no shorter one.
对了  有  小时候
Oh yes, there is, When I was a kid,
我帮我老子从边届赶一些牛来
I helped my old man traiI some cattle up from the border.
艾黛丽安  你听得见吗？
Can you hear me, Adrian?
听好  听好
Keep listening. Keep listening.
布鲁斯看到牛群被追走
After breakfast, Bruce watched the party get away on the chase.
他见科拉和凯和巴德从谷里上来
He saw Cora and Kay and Bud
超前15分钟
start up the valley 15 minutes ahead of the others.
最后一分女孩们
At the last minute, the girl
欧佳回道  巴克梅森  他是谁？
replied, Olga, Buck Mason, who is he?
艾黛丽安  我为你写这篇东西
I just wrote this thing for you, Adrian.
或许你会喜欢它
Maybe you'll like it.
我来读给你听
I'll just read it.
还记得我们一起溜冰
Remember when we was on ice-skates
而且我认为你应该很会溜的
And I thought you was supposed to be great
可是  我一直让你滑倒
But I kept giving you lip,
你也一直滑倒
And you kept trying to slip
就可一直扶着你
So I could catch you.
那就是我们第一次的约会
And that was our first date
从那次以后
And after that
日子都变得美妙起来
every day was great.
所以我要告诉你  无论天涯海角
So now, I want ya to know, That wherever you go
亚特兰市或雪地里
Atlantic City or in the snow
你一点都不要担心
Don't worry 'bout a thing,
只要我戴上这只戒指
Because as long as I got this ring
我永远都会扶着你
I'll always be there to catch you.
我就知道你会醒过来
I knew you'd come back.
感谢上帝！
Thanks, God!
谁还要再来一点？
Anybody want a refill?
艾黛丽安  一瓶六块钱
Adrian, it costs six bucks a bottle.
不  我现在不喝
I don't need that. I ain't drinking now.
你没看过小孩子吗？
You mean you haven't seen the baby?
没有  我想等你一起去看
No, come on. I was waiting to see him together.
孩子是胜利者
You know, the kid's a winner.
他有一双强壮手臂
He's got full arms like you, Mickey.
他来了  瞧
Here he is now. Look.
宝贝！
My baby!
那就是？
Is that it?
我不敢相信！他是我们生的
I can't believe it! He's ours?
真是我们的？谢谢
He's really ours? Thank you.
艾黛丽安  我不敢相信你已生了他！
Adrian, I can't believe you done this!
相信我  我们已经有了孩子
Believe me, we did.
你想替他取什么名字？
What do you wanna call him?
保利的名字不错
Paulie's a great name.
保利是个不错的名字
Paul, Paulie's a pretty good name.
取个像爸爸的名字怎么样？
What about after the father?
小洛奇？
Rocky Junior?
你真要用这名字？对
Come on, you really want to do that?
艾黛丽安  他是我所见的婴儿里面最好看的一个
Adrian, he's the best I've ever seen.
你看起来很累
You look so tired.
你为什么不去睡个觉？
Why don't you go get some sleep?
不  我觉得很好
No, no. I feel great. Listen, I've been thinking.
我再跟奎迪来往的话.
If you don't want me mixing with Creed no more
我们想点别的办法
we'll make out some other kinda way, you know.
我要你为我作一件事
There's one thing I want you to do for me.
什么事？
What?
你靠过来一下
Come here.
什么事？
What?
赢！
Win!
我们还等什么？赶快答应呀！
What're we waiting for? Take this!
再快一点！
Faster! Faster!
继续！
Keep moving, keep moving!
快点！
Faster!
跳高点！连着跳
Pick 'em up! Pace doubles.
对了
That's it.
对
速度！速度！
Speed! Speed!
快点！
Come on!
别偷懒！
Don't give up!
加油
Come on
44… 45…
44 45
46… 47…
46 47
48… 49…
48 49
别放弃！用尽全力！
Don't give up! Get that other out of you!
推！
Push!
41… 42… 43…
41 42 43
46… 47…
46 47
推！再来！
Push! Again!
左  右
Left. Right.
我抓到了！
I did it!
这才是速度！
That's speed!
速度！速度！
Speed! Speed!
晚安
Good night.
我做到了！
I made it!
洛奇！
Rocky!
女士们  先生们  晚上好  我是比利·波温
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. This is Bill Baldwin speaking to you
史贝川体育馆内向各位报导
from the magnificent Spectrum,
位于费城
here in Philadelphia
第二次超级拳赛所在地
the site of Superfight Two
挑战者  洛奇·巴尔博亚与
with Rocky Balboa, the challenger,
世界拳王  阿波罗·奎迪
of course, Apollo Creed, the world champion.
史都南汉今晚再度主持
My sidekick and partner again tonight, Stu Nahan.
谢谢
Thank you, Bill.
各位今晚将欣间一场真正的大赛
we're gonna see a real great battle, in every sense of the word.
什么都不要担心
Don't worry about nothing.
没问题的
It's okay.
我得走了
I gotta go.
真希望医生同意你去观赛
Adrian, I wish the doctor'd let you go to this fight.
我也这么希望
Me too.
你是拳王  始终最棒的一位.
You're the man. You're Number One. The champ, the best of all time.
女孩子喜欢你  大家喜欢你
The girIs love you. Men will always love you.
你最棒  他就要被你打败
You're the best. You're the man. And he's yours.
这无赖根本没资格跟你比赛
This bum shouldn't even be in the same ring with you.
我们该给他一点教训
I want you to show him who you are tonight.
让他试试苦头！
Show him who you are. Stick him!
洛奇
Rocky
你要帮忙照顾小孩吗？
Listen, Paulie, you're gonna help out with the baby tonight.
好吧  凡事就请你多费点心吧
You just take care of everything now,
你会来不及参加比赛了
You're gonna be late for your fight.
一切都会很好
Everything's gonna be fine.
我最好现在就走
Maybe I better go fight now.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
And I love you, too.
艾黛丽安  希望你能来参观
Adrian, I wish you could go.
医生说不行
The doctor said, no.
保重祝你好运
Take care.Good luck.
拳王自称目前处于颠峰状态
The champion has let it be known that he is in the best shape of his illustrious career.
洛奇·巴尔博亚
Rocky Balboa
获胜率只有五分之一
is a five-to-one underdog.
我知道  他还是费城的街头选手
Still a street brawler from Philadelphia.
他是否能再现
But can he repeat that
十个月前的精彩表现？
incredible performance of 10 months ago?
他对拳王构成很大威胁
He took a real beating at the hands of the champion.
卡麦神父！
Father Carmine!
卡麦神父你在家吗？
Hey, Father Carmine, you home?
卡麦神父！
Father Carmine!
洛奇吗？
Rocky?
我是洛奇·巴尔博亚
It's me, Rocky Balboa.
- 洛奇？- 对 是我
- Rocky?  - Yes.
（意大利语）你怎么来了？你不是应该去比赛吗？
( Speak in Italian )
对  我就要去参加比赛
I'm going to the fight right now.
你能否帮我一个小忙？
But I was wondering if you could do me a small favor, you know?
是关于比赛的事
It's about the fight, you know.
现在我成了家  有了孩子
Now I got the family and the baby and all that stuff.
你能否赐福予我
if you could throw down a blessing.
万一我今晚挨了打  也不致于太惨
So if I get beat up tonight it won't be too bad, you know.
你能帮帮忙吗？
Could you do something like that?
多谢神父  我很感激
Thanks a lot, Father. I appreciate it.
我要走了  我迟到了
I gotta go. I'm so late.
我会再到教堂来  保重
I'll see ya in church, I hope. Take care.
嘿  洛奇
Hey, Rocky.
祝好运
Good luck, son.
你糊涂了  是吗？快点
Where you been? You lost your brains or something?
我们今晚要参加比赛  还记得吗？
We got a fight here tonight, remember?
对不起  我迟了
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I'm here.
快去换衣服
Get dressed, will you?
关于这场比赛有很多流言
There are many rumors about this fight.
传的最多就是
The most obvious being a definite desire
阿波罗要迅速出击  速战速决
for Apollo to draw first blood, to end it quickly.
这样证明他所说的上回比赛只是侥幸而已
This would prove his claim that the last fight was a fluke.
加油  闪电！雷电！
Lightning! Thunder!
飓风！飓风！
Hurricane! Hurricane!
你就要把他制服
You're gonna get him.
他是我们的
He's ours. He's ours.
该上场了  孩子
It's time, kid.
好  我们走吧
Okay, let's do it.
好  我准备好了
All right, I'm ready.
我好像开始头痛了
I think I'm starting to get a headache here.
不  你的状态很完美  很完美
No, you are in perfect working condition.
你状态也不错
You look real good, too.
谢谢  你看起来好极了
And you look perfect.
嘿  米奇
Hey, Mick
假如我没有成功的机会
In case I don't get a chance,
我仍要告诉你
I just wanna say
今晚我会为你努力的
I'm gonna be trying hard for you today, okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
这件袍子不错吧？
Ain't this robe nice?
绝对比去年的那件布袋子强多了
It's better than the last one. Remember that baggy one?
这件很漂亮  很完美
This is gorgeous. It's perfect.
对  确实好看  我喜欢
It's real cute. I like it.
洛奇·巴尔博亚往场里走了
Here's Rocky Balboa heading toward the ring now.
众人所熟悉的意大利种马
known to millions as The Italian Stallion
为什么这位能力有限的拳手
Why this fighter of limited ability
会赢得众人的喜爱
has gained such popularity
实在令人费解
is such a mystery.
洛奇·巴尔博亚！
Rocky Balboa!
这里的观众开始狂呼其名
And the crowds here in this section are beginning to chant his name.
在场有许多他的拥护者
He has an awfuI lot of backers here.
巴尔博亚穿一件金黑色袍子
Balboa is wearing a black-and-gold robe.
上回他穿了一件
He wore a red one the last time
肉类包装店的红上衣
from that meat-packing plant.
有些人说那是他
Some said that was from the high school
从未毕业的高中时代的衣服
that he never graduated from Thirty-one years of age.
我们现在等待拳王入场
And we're waiting now for the champion to come into the ring.
洛奇！
Rocky!
拳场挤满了洛奇的拳迷
The arena's certainly packed with Rocky's people.
我从未看过这么多意大利人
I've never seen so many Italians in one place in my life.
是你说的  我没有
You said it, I didn't say it.
洛奇！洛奇！
Rocky! Rocky!
这些人都是来为你加油的  洛奇！
These people are for you, Rocky!
很感激
I appreciate it.
你的头痛好了吗？我想好了
Are you ready in here? I think so.
今晚是我们之夜
Tonight's our night, kid.
拳王开始入场…
By the sound of the crowd,the champion is just now coming into the Spectrum.
冠军阿波罗·奎迪
And the champion, Apollo Creed.
他这次看起来更有决心！
He looks a little more determined this time than he did the last time!
是阿波罗你想会是谁？
It's Apollo.Who'd ya expect?
我还希望他不来
I was hoping he wouldn't show.
拳王现在进到绳圈来
And now, the champion is climbing into the ring
很有把握的样子
very determined-looking, very serious right now.
洛奇看起来不像他有信心
Rocky doesn't look as confident as he might.
阿波罗·奎迪  永恒之王！
Apollo Creed, the master of disaster!
你就要被击倒！你完了！
You going down, man! You going down!
别操心  孩子
Don't let it bother you, kid.
你会操心吗？
Wouldn't it bother you?
女士们  先生们  晚安
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
欢迎到费城的史贝川体育馆来
And welcome to the Philadelphia Spectrum.
这是今晚的大事的拳赛里
This is the main event of the evening:
15轮  争夺重量级拳王大赛
Fifteen rounds, the Heavyweight Championship of the world.
站在黑色的角落里是
In the black corner,
挑战者  体重202旁
the challenger weighing 202 pounds.
来自拳击之城的费城
From the great fighting city of Philadelphia
意大利种马的洛奇·巴尔博亚
The ltalian Stallion, Rocky Balboa.
一位世界闻名的拳王
a champion
不须要我再来介绍
who needs no introduction anywhere in the civilized world.
真正的一位败北的克星
The true master of disaster
一位永击不败的世界重量级拳王
the undefeated Heavyweight Champion of the world
阿波罗·奎迪
the one, the only, Apollo Creed.
裁判现在指示他们
Referee Lou Filippo will give the instructions.
好  两位
I'm gonna give you
比赛规则是
the instructions now.
希望遵守
I expect you to follow them.
不可以攻击腰部以下的部位
Watch your low punches
还有不可以攻击腰部
and watch your kidney punches.
也不可以由背部击头部
Watch your rabbit punches.
假如被击倒
In case of a knockdown,
你们回到自己的角落去
you go to the corner I tell you to
待在那里等我口号知道吗？
and stay there until I tell you to come out. Understand?
希望比赛圆满
Okay, boys, let's have a good fight.
你就要倒地
You're going down.
祝你好运
Good luck to you.
他还在气头上
He's still upset.
谁理他？护着那只眼
Who cares? Now listen, protect that eye.
除非我叫你  否则不要用左拳打
And no matter what happens don't go back to fighting southpaw till I tell you.
你就会打倒他明白吗？好
Now, you get him, son.
祝你好运  祝好运
Rocky, good luck.
他想快速把你打倒
Now, he's gonna try to kill you quick.
只要你能度过第一个回合  那他铁定败在我们手下！
If you get through this first round, then he's ours!
让他知道你的厉害
Show him who you are.
洛奇在祈祷  拳王在挥舞
Rocky Balboa prays in his corner. The champion dancing over in his corner.
世纪性的拳赛即将开始
We're just seconds away from the fight of the century, Superfight Two.
拳王快速挥拳进攻
The champion comes over in a hurry and throws a couple of rights and lefts.
他一开始就占优势
He starts to take command early here.
他努力保持速度
And now, he's kind of hauling speed around the ring.
洛奇用右手比赛
Rocky's holding that right hand.
对付那猛击  他用右拳
He's fighting right-handed.
不可思议
I don't believe it.
南费城仔用右手！
The Southpaw from Philly, he is fighting right-handed!
洛奇！
Rocky!
痛击他呀！
Break that damn jab!
保护那只眼睛！
Protect that eye!
这就是你全部的本领？
Is that all you got? You ain't got nothing!
你要卧下了吗？
You ready to lay down?
又是准准的一下右拳
A go right, a go left.
又是一拳！
Another right and another right!
狠狠三记右拳
Creed out with a right hand. Take it, Balboa.
洛奇退到角落
Now he's in the corner.
左右拳轮番猛烈还击
And those left and right hits are coming back at him.
拳王打中洛奇的头洛奇退到绳上
A lot of lefts and a right to the head.
洛奇不断被击中
Balboa appears to be getting hit often.
不过状况好像很好
But he seems to be in pretty good condition right now.
洛奇好像碰上困难了
Balboa is in trouble now.
他连连中拳
He's in trouble, taking rights and lefts from the champion.
他好像无力招架了
It is a tremendous fight
洛奇被击倒了
Balboa is down
阿波罗打中他的坏左眼
We see Apollo's hit that bad left eye,
还记得吗？和上一场被打伤的同一只眼
remember,from the first fight? It was the eye that was cut the last time.
巴尔博亚站起来了
Balboa's getting up.
宰了他！
Go get him!
追他  追他！好！
Go after him, kid! Go after him!
拳王再度入场
The champion starts to move in again,
他挥出右拳左拳
throwing rights and lefts
巴尔博亚一轮猛攻越过场子
Balboa right into the cord.
加油！巴尔博亚！
Come on! Balboa!
巴尔博亚连中数拳
Balboa's tags: Left, left and right combinations by the champion.
这一回合结束
It's the end of the round.
这二人水火不容
There's a lot of bad blood between these two.
这一回合打得不错
Good round. Good round.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
他又打中我的鼻子
He broke my nose again.
巴尔博亚一定要很壮
Balboa's gotta be in great shape
才耐得了这种残杀的考验
to withstand that butchering.
就是这样子  残杀
And I'll tell you just what it is, it's a plain old butchering.
他换手有没有干扰你？
Did the switching bother you?
那你早该打倒他了
All right, then you should've had him.
你很强悍  不会受伤的！
you can't be hurt, Because you are too tough!
别给他机会  这个小子很危险
Now, don't let up on this man. This man is dangerous.
他危险！我才是最危险的！
This man is danger! I am dangerous!
那家伙很厉害
That guy's great.
不  不  他只是个人而已
Listen, he's only a man.
你可以把他击倒
You can beat him
因为你是坦克
because you're a tank.
你有速度  你是个二百磅重的
You're a greasy, fast, 200-pound
意大利坦克
Italian tank.
去打他！碾死他！
Go to him! Run over him!
我是坦克  我要打倒他！
I'm a tank. I'm gonna get him!
让我结束这比赛吧  第二回合
Here we go, round 2.
拳王一出场  他立刻猛攻
The champion comes back out.
他不断出左拳攻击对方
He's leading across again starting with the left to the left,to the left.
左头  左颊  左眼  不断出拳
Left to the chin. Left to the head. Left to the chin. Left to the head.
他以左拳攻击
He's coming on now. They're pulling out that right hand.
只是在等候准确的一刻！
He's just waiting for that precise moment that he wants. There it is!
巴尔博亚突然出拳攻击！
And here comes Balboa!
你伤不了我  你绝伤不了我！
You can't hurt me. He can't hurt me, no way!
分开  拉开来
Break it up. Break it up.
分开  分开
Break it up. Break free.
巴尔博亚出拳
Now the champion holds Balboa.
你太慢了！
You're too slow! Man, you're too slow!
你们准备好照相机
Get your cameras ready.
看  他就要倒地！
Watch this, man, watch this!
他要倒了
He's going down.
洛奇  起来  起来！
Get up, Rocky, get up!
巴尔博亚第二次倒下  他起来了
Balboa for the second time is down, struggling to get up.
就卧在那里  呆子
Just stay down there, chump.
漂亮  漂亮
Beautiful. Beautiful.
7… 8…
Seven...eight....
护着那只眼  孩子！
Protect that eye, kid!
目标身体！身体！
Get at it! Your body!
你是部坦克  孩子
You're a tank, kid.
我早说过了
I told you.
拳王走向拳台中央
Here comes the champion
这次  1  2  就好  1  2
One, two. One, two.
现一左拳  一右拳
But here it is. A left and a right,
他把他逼回角落
and he's got him back in the corner.
巴尔博亚退到角落
Balboa's back in the corner.
巴尔博亚又开始反击了  他从哪来的持久力？
Here comes Balboa again. Where does he get that stamina?
他把拳王逼在角落  逼死在角落
He's got the champion trapped over in the corner.
洛奇！
Rocky!
别停！继续！
Keep it up! Keep it up!
来啊
Come on.
分开来
Break it up.
我在这里
I'm standing here.
他们仍在互相对骂
And they're taunting each other.
钟声已响过  他们还在互骂！
The battle, the round is over.But they're taunting each other!
各位观众准备看
Everybody in the audience get ready
第三次世界大战的爆发！
for World War III!
我不会再倒下
I ain't goin' down no more.
对  去找他算帐
That a boy. Go get him.
放开  老弟  打
Come on boys, break it up. Break it.
分开
Break it up.
拳王又一次左右拳轮攻
The champion again, with a combination of lefts and rights to the head
又是另一个回合
That was another round for Creed.
阿波罗·奎迪得分的回合
Creed's just piling up the points.
打他  洛奇！
Hit him, Rocky!
打他！
Hit him!
打他！打！
Hit him! Just hit him!
阿波罗又赢得了这回合
Another round for Apollo Creed.
加油  洛奇！
Come on, Rocky!
巴尔博亚得分的回合又开始了
Creed's in the corner.
阿波罗第一次失利的回合
Left and right to the midsection. Those hurt.
打身体
Hold that body.
另一拳王得分的回合
He's won another round.
他又开始痛击巴尔博亚
He now begins to pound Balboa's head.
闪开！
Get out!
这一回合我会判巴尔博亚胜
I'm gonna give that round to Balboa.
我在想此刻阿波罗心里怎么想
You wonder what's on Apollo Creed's mind right now.
他第一回合输了
He's lost his first round.
打头  洛奇！
Go for it, Rocky!
打得好
Looks great.
来吧
Come on.
手举高！只要盯紧出拳！
Come on! Hands up! Now just stick and move!
这个人要你中内伤  盯紧挥拳！
This man is breaking you up inside. Stick and move!
举起来
Keep your hands up.
还击！
Hit him back!
我想他今晚所中的拳
He took a beating 10 months ago,
重于十月前的两倍
but tonight, it's twice as bad.
拳王又赢一回合
Another round for the champion, Apollo Creed.
他左眼已经闭起来
The left eye is closed.
现在把他解决掉
Now bust him, understand? Keep working on him.
离他远一点
Stay away from him.
不要让他呼吸
Don't let him breathe.
打倒他！
Get him!
来吧
Come on.
老天！
God!
巴尔博亚又在角落挨打
Balboa's taking another beating in the corner.
另一属于拳王得分的回合
Another round for the champion.
洛奇  洛奇！
Rocky! Rocky!
你得打他要害！
Now you gotta beat him on points. You understand?!
现在看住他移动！
Now, stick and move!
他就要倒下
He's gonna fall.
不要想一拳把他打倒！
Don't go for the knockout!
那只眼怎样了？
How's that eye, now?
还管用！
It works!
你支持不住了  对吧？
You can't do much more with that, can you?
我知道该怎么做！
I know what I'm doing!
洛奇  你若有困难我就判停
You get in trouble one more time, I'm gonna stop
请你不要停止比赛
Please don't stop nothing.
停止比赛  你就要被杀了！
Let me stop it because you're getting killed!
那是我的生命！
It's my life!
拳王只要离对手远点
Apollo's well ahead.
那他仍保有原来的封号
All he has to do is stay away and he retains the title.
只要看住移动  明白吗？
Just stick and move, you understand?!
只要看住移动！
Just stick and move!
这次跟上回不一样
It ain't gonna be like last time.
现在改用左拳
Switch now to southpaw anyway, will you?
不  我不要用左拳耍诈
No tricks, I ain't switching.
可是你就要宣告不支
But you're fading out, kid.
我不要玩诈！
I don't need no tricks!
好  去吧！
All right! Go with the right.
你要想想  你得要变一下
You got a plan, you gotta switch, kid.
他在等你
He's ready, believe me.
阿波罗  别想击倒  你要逃
Apollo, don't go for the knockout.
15回合开始  最后一回合
They've come to the center of the ring for the 15th and final round.
你要倒了  不  绝不
You're going down. No, no way.
开始  看奎迪的表现了
Here we go. Let's see what Creed does here now.
一开始奎迪冲向巴尔博亚
Creed is starting to move in on Balboa. He's going for the knockdown.
拳王以左拳猛攻不停
The champion comes off jabbing with that left hand. Sticking the left hand out.
快！快！
Now! Now!
巴尔博亚快击倒拳王！
Balboa has nearly floored the champ!
他的一记勾拳打垮了耗尽的拳王！
His left hook caught the exhausted champ off guard!
奎迪完全昏了
Creed doesn't know where he is. It's blind instinct.
巴尔博亚无力缓慢移动
Balboa is staggering from exhaustion.
局势完全改观
Apollo is barely protecting himself.
一记右拳打中拳王
A right to the head of the champion.
又一记左拳打中拳王！
Another right! A left to the head!
离他远点！
Stay away from him!
他若远离一定会赢
Balboa tries to stay away,
奎迪反击了  用他的左拳
but now it is Creed coming back. Creed with the left hand.
别跟他打！
Go for it! What're you waiting for?!
是什么支撑着这两个人？
What's keeping these two guys up?
现在！
Now!
巴尔博亚出拳
Here comes Balboa.
但拳王还以一记左拳！
But the champ came back with another left!
离开他！
Get away from him!
他们会如何  我不知道！
Where are they getting it, I don't know!
一记右拳！是奎迪
A right hand! A right hand! It's Creed.
现在是巴尔博亚！
Now it's Balboa!
是奎迪
It's Creed.
奎迪挥一记很重的左拳
A tremendous,
现在他们已拼命尽全力
tough fight.
不懂拳王为何打巴尔博亚！
They're sending deadness up to the ring!
洛奇！
Rocky!
加油  好呀！
Come on! Good!
洛奇
Rocky
奎迪将保住王位
Creed will retain the title if he's up.
若两人都起不来  奎迪将保住王位！
Then Creed will win the title automatically!
起来  老兄！
Get up, my man!
你起来呀！
Get on your feet!
巴尔博亚抓到第二根
Now Rocky Balboa reaches for another....
起来！洛奇！起来！
Get up! Rocky! Get up!
他要及时起来
Balboa's trying to get up
拳王也在努力
Now the champ is trying to get up.
拳王依然在苦苦挣扎！
The champ can't make it! He slips down again.
阿波罗挣扎着想起起来！
He is trying to get up!
起来！
Get Up!
拳王倒下了  他倒了  起来！
The champ is still on one knee! Get up!
出局！他赢了！巴尔博亚赢了！
It's over! He won! Balboa just legally did it!
洛奇·巴尔博亚震惊全世界！
Rocky has shocked the world!
他是新任世界重量级拳王
He is the new Heavyweight Champion of the world.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
结果出乎意料  击倒取胜的是…
in a stunning upset scoring the winning-point knockout
新任世界重量级拳王  洛奇
the new Heavyweight Champion of the world, Rocky
你很棒
You're great.
洛奇·巴尔博亚
Rocky Balboa
祝你好运
Good luck.
对不起！对不起！
Excuse me! Excuse me!
我不敢相信这是真的  我不敢
I can't believe this has happened. I can't.
我要谢谢阿波罗
And I just wanna say thanks to Apollo.
给我向他挑战的机会
For fighting me, Apollo.
谢谢米奇训练我
I wanna thank Mickey for training me....
我们爱戴你  洛奇！
We love you, Rocky!
我也爱你们！
And I love you, too!
特别是  我要感谢上帝
Most of all, I wanna thank God.
除了我儿子出世以外
Except for my kid being born
今晚是我有生以来
this is the greatest night
最了不起的一夜
in the history of my life.
我要向在家里的太太说句话
I just wanna say one thing to my wife who's home.
艾黛丽安  我做到了！
Adrian, I did it!
我爱你  我爱你
I love you. I love you.
谢谢观赏
DR·Lee   倾情奉献
2016 年 10 月